Title_1	Introduction_1	Preparation_time_1	Cooking_1	Ingredient_1_1	Ingredient_2_1	Ingredient_3_1	Ingredient_4_1	Ingredient_5_1	Ingredient_6_1	Ingredient_7_1	Ingredient_8_1	Ingredient_9_1	Ingredient_10_1	Ingredient_11_1	Ingredient_12_1	Ingredient_13_1	Instruction_1_1	Instruction_2_1	Instruction_3_1	Instruction_4_1	Instruction_5_1	Instruction_6_1	Instruction_7_1	Variation_1	Storage_1	Calories_1	Protein_1	Fiber_1	Carbs_1	TotalFat_1	SaturatedFat_1	TotalSugars_1	AddedSugars_1	Sodium_1	@Image_1	Title_2	Introduction_2	Preparation_time_2	Cooking_2	Ingredient_1_2	Ingredient_2_2	Ingredient_3_2	Ingredient_4_2	Ingredient_5_2	Ingredient_6_2	Ingredient_7_2	Ingredient_8_2	Ingredient_9_2	Ingredient_10_2	Ingredient_11_2	Ingredient_12_2	Ingredient_13_2	Instruction_1_2	Instruction_2_2	Instruction_3_2	Instruction_4_2	Instruction_5_2	Instruction_6_2	Instruction_7_2	Variation_2	Storage_2	Calories_2	Protein_2	Fiber_2	Carbs_2	TotalFat_2	SaturatedFat_2	TotalSugars_2	AddedSugars_2	Sodium_2	@Image_2
Chickpea and Spinach Shakshuka	This simple, single-skillet meal requires minimal prep and cooks completely on the stovetop. Eggs, chickpeas, and spinach simmer in a spiced tomato sauce for a hearty start to the day.	5 min	13–19 min	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1/2 medium Yellow onion, diced	2 cloves Garlic, minced	1 tsp (2 g) Ground cumin	1/2 tsp (1 g) Smoked paprika	1 tsp (5 ml) Red wine vinegar	14.5 oz (411 g) No-salt-added canned diced tomatoes, undrained	1/2 cup (130 g) No-salt-added canned chickpeas, rinsed and drained	3 cups (90 g) Baby spinach	4 Large eggs	1/2 cup (113 g) Nonfat plain Greek yogurt	1 large (60 g) Whole-wheat pita bread, halved		Heat oil in a large skillet over medium heat. Add onion and cook until softened, 3 to 4 minutes.	Stir in garlic, cumin, and smoked paprika. Cook, stirring constantly, for 1 to 2 minutes.	Pour in vinegar, tomatoes, and chickpeas. Bring to a simmer over medium-high heat, then lower heat to medium-low and simmer until the sauce thickens slightly, 4 to 5 minutes.	Stir spinach into the skillet in handfuls. Cook until the leaves are bright green and wilted, 1 to 2 minutes.	Form shallow wells in the hot tomato mixture using a spoon. Crack an egg into each well.	Cover the skillet with a lid and cook over low heat until the egg whites are firm but the yolks remain soft, 4 to 6 minutes.	Remove the skillet from the heat. Divide the warm shakshuka between plates and serve immediately with Greek yogurt and pita bread.	Trade the spinach for chopped curly kale and simmer longer.	Best enjoyed right away; does not keep.	445 kcal	28.3 g	8.7 g	41.5 g	20.0 g	4.4 g	11.8 g	0.0 g*	459 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Breakfast\IMG\15-minute_chickpea_and_spinach_shakshuka.png	Blueberry-Oat Cottage Cheese Pancakes	For a satisfying breakfast that feels like a weekend treat, these hearty pancakes deliver lasting morning fuel. Whole oats and cottage cheese blend into a protein-rich batter topped with an instant blueberry jam.	10 min	10–15 min	1 1/2 cups (210 g) Frozen blueberries	1 tbsp (12 g) Chia seeds	1 cup (226 g) No-salt-added low-fat cottage cheese	1 cup (80 g) Rolled oats	3 large (150 g) Large eggs	3 tbsp (30 g) Hemp hearts	1 tsp (4 g) Baking powder	1 tsp (2 g) Ground cinnamon	1 tsp (5 ml) Vanilla extract	1 tsp (5 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil				Combine the frozen blueberries and chia seeds in a microwave-safe bowl, then microwave on high for 2 to 3 minutes until bubbling and bursting.	Blend the cottage cheese, oats, eggs, hemp hearts, baking powder, cinnamon, and vanilla extract in a blender on high until the batter is smooth.	Heat a large nonstick skillet over medium heat and brush with the olive oil until shimmering.	Pour the batter into the pan in small circles to form the pancakes.	Cook the pancakes in batches for 4 to 6 minutes per batch, flipping halfway through when the edges appear set and the bottoms are golden brown.	Transfer the finished pancakes to a plate and repeat until all the batter is used.	Divide the warm pancakes between plates and spoon the thickened blueberry-chia jam over the top.	Swap the frozen blueberries for frozen dark sweet cherries.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; reheat pancakes in a dry skillet.	539 kcal	34.9 g	10.1 g	49.0 g	23.2 g	4.8 g	13.3 g	0.0 g*	339 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Breakfast\IMG\blueberry-oat_cottage_cheese_pancakes.png
Creamy Mixed Berry and Almond Smoothie Bowls	This simple no-cook breakfast requires only a quick blitz in the blender. Silken tofu, frozen berries, and creamy almond butter combine into a remarkably thick base that keeps hunger away until lunch.	10 min	none (no-cook)	16 oz (450 g) Silken tofu, drained	3/4 cup (180 ml) Unsweetened soy milk	2 cups (280 g) Frozen mixed berries	1 medium (118 g) Banana, peeled and broken into pieces	2 tbsp (32 g) Creamy almond butter	2 tbsp (24 g) Chia seeds	1/2 cup (40 g) Old-fashioned rolled oats	1/2 tsp (1 g) Cinnamon						Place the drained silken tofu, unsweetened soy milk, frozen mixed berries, banana, creamy almond butter, chia seeds, rolled oats, and cinnamon into a high-speed blender.	Blend on low speed to incorporate the dry and frozen ingredients into the liquids.	Increase the speed to high and blend until completely smooth and remarkably thick, stopping once or twice to scrape down the sides or use a blender tamper as needed.	Divide the thick mixture evenly between two bowls and serve immediately.				Swap the creamy almond butter for unsweetened natural peanut butter.	Best enjoyed right away; does not keep.	517 kcal	27.7 g	13.1 g	56.4 g	21.9 g	2.5 g	20.2 g	0.0 g*	119 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Breakfast\IMG\creamy_mixed_berry_and_almond_smoothie_bowls.png	Fluffy Egg White Oatmeal with Berries and Walnuts	This simple stovetop technique transforms ordinary oats into a creamy, filling morning meal. Simmering rolled oats with liquid egg whites creates a thick bowl without relying on protein powders.	5 min	7–10 min	1 cup (240 ml) Water	1 cup (240 ml) Unsweetened almond milk	1 cup (80 g) Old-fashioned rolled oats	1 tsp (2 g) Ground cinnamon	1/8 tsp (0.5 g) Kosher salt	1 3/4 cups (400 g) Liquid egg whites	1 1/2 cups (200 g) Frozen mixed berries	1 tsp (5 ml) Vanilla extract	1/4 cup (30 g) Walnuts, chopped					Combine the water, almond milk, oats, cinnamon, and salt in a medium saucepan. Bring the mixture to a rolling boil over medium-high heat.	Reduce the heat to low to maintain a gentle simmer. Cook the oats for 5 to 7 minutes, checking at 5 minutes, until the liquid is absorbed and the oats are tender.	Pour the liquid egg whites into the simmering oats in a slow stream while stirring vigorously to prevent scrambling.	Cook and stir the mixture for 2 to 3 minutes, checking at 2 minutes, until it becomes thick and the egg whites are opaque.	Remove the saucepan from the heat. Stir in the frozen berries and vanilla extract so the residual heat thaws the fruit.	Divide the warm oatmeal between two bowls. Top with the chopped walnuts before serving.		Swap the chopped walnuts for sliced almonds or toasted pecans.	Best enjoyed right away; does not keep.	417 kcal	29.1 g	7.8 g	43.9 g	13.8 g	1.5 g	8.8 g	0.0 g*	528 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Breakfast\IMG\fluffy_egg_white_oatmeal_with_berries_and_walnuts.png
Lemony Sardine and Avocado Whole-Grain Toast	Start the day with a substantial hit of lean protein and fiber for steady energy and lasting fullness.	10 min	none (no-cook)	4 slices (136 g) Low-sodium sprouted whole-grain bread, toasted	3.5 oz (100 g) Avocado, pitted and peeled	1 tbsp (15 ml) Fresh lemon juice	1 tsp (2 g) Fresh lemon zest, finely grated	1.5 oz (40 g) Baby arugula	5 oz (150 g) Cherry tomatoes, halved	2 cans (212 g) No-salt-added canned sardines in water, drained	1/4 tsp (1 g) Crushed red pepper flakes	5 oz (150 g) Fresh strawberries, hulled and halved					Toast the bread until golden and crisp.	Mash the avocado in a bowl with the lemon juice and lemon zest until combined but slightly chunky.	Spread the mashed avocado evenly across the toast slices.	Layer the baby arugula and halved cherry tomatoes over the avocado.	Break the drained sardines into large pieces with a fork and arrange them on top of the vegetables.	Sprinkle the crushed red pepper flakes evenly over the toasts.	Serve immediately with the fresh strawberries on the side.	Trade the baby arugula for fresh baby spinach leaves.	Best enjoyed right away; assembled toast does not keep.	448 kcal	32.5 g	12.3 g	44.9 g	17.5 g	3.0 g	6.6 g	0.0 g*	138 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Breakfast\IMG\lemony_sardine_and_avocado_whole-grain_toast.png	Mediterranean Salmon and Hummus Breakfast Wraps	This fast, no-cook breakfast is ready to eat as quickly as you can mix and assemble the ingredients. Flaky canned salmon and creamy hummus replace traditional breakfast meats to create a morning wrap that prevents mid-morning hunger.	10 min	none (no-cook)	2 (90 g) Whole-wheat tortillas, 6-inch fajita size	8.5 oz (240 g) Canned pink salmon (no-salt-added), rinsed and drained, flaked	1/3 cup (80 g) Plain hummus	1 tbsp (15 ml) Fresh lemon juice	1 tbsp (3 g) Fresh dill, chopped	1/4 tsp (1 g) Black pepper	2 cups (60 g) Baby spinach	1 cup (100 g) English cucumber, diced	1/4 cup (40 g) Red onion, thinly sliced	1 1/2 cups (220 g) Fresh mixed berries				Flake the salmon with a fork in a medium bowl.	Stir the hummus, lemon juice, dill, and black pepper into the salmon until combined.	Lay the whole-wheat tortillas flat on a clean workspace and distribute the baby spinach evenly over each.	Spoon the salmon and hummus mixture evenly over the spinach.	Top with the diced cucumber and sliced red onion.	Roll the tortillas tightly to form firm wraps.	Serve the wraps immediately with the fresh berries on the side.	Swap the baby spinach for fresh arugula or baby kale.	Best enjoyed right away; does not keep well once assembled.	471 kcal	38.1 g	13.9 g	43.0 g	18.0 g	4.2 g	8.9 g	0.0 g*	558 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Breakfast\IMG\mediterranean_salmon_and_hummus_breakfast_wraps.png
Minty Smashed Green Pea and Egg Toasts	Cool mint and a creamy yogurt-pea mash top crisp whole-grain toast in this savory, satisfying breakfast.	10 min	4–6 min	1 cup (130 g) Frozen green peas	1/3 cup (75 g) Nonfat plain Greek yogurt	1 tbsp (15 ml) Lemon juice	2 tbsp (3 g) Fresh mint, finely chopped	1/2 tsp (1 g) Garlic powder	2 large (100 g) Large eggs	1/2 cup (120 ml) Liquid egg whites	1 tsp (5 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	4 slices (112 g) 100% whole-wheat bread	2 tbsp (15 g) Feta cheese, crumbled	1 cup (144 g) Fresh strawberries, sliced			Boil water in a small pot over high heat. Add the peas, cook for 2 to 3 minutes until tender, and drain well.	Transfer the warm peas to a bowl. Add the yogurt, lemon juice, mint, and garlic powder, mashing with a fork until chunky but spreadable.	Whisk the whole eggs and egg whites together in a small bowl until fully blended.	Heat the olive oil in a skillet over medium-low heat. Pour in the eggs and cook for 2 to 3 minutes, stirring gently until soft curds form.	Toast the whole-wheat bread slices.	Spread the minted pea mash evenly over the warm toasts. Top with the scrambled eggs and crumbled feta.	Serve immediately alongside the sliced fresh strawberries.	Swap the fresh mint for fresh dill or chopped basil.	Best enjoyed right away; assembled toasts do not keep.	386 kcal	28.6 g	7.8 g	42.5 g	11.5 g	3.4 g	11.2 g	0.0 g*	576 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Breakfast\IMG\minty_smashed_green_pea_and_egg_toasts.png	Open-Faced Tomato and Spinach Egg Melts	This energizing breakfast transforms a heavy morning sandwich into a satisfying open-faced meal. A mix of eggs piled over whole wheat muffins with fresh tomato, mozzarella, and a side of strawberries keeps you full until lunch.	10 min	4–6 min	2 (114 g) 100% whole wheat English muffins, split	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	2 cups (60 g) Baby spinach	2 large (100 g) Whole eggs	2/3 cup (150 ml) Liquid egg whites	1/2 tsp (1 g) Black pepper	1 medium (120 g) Fresh tomato, sliced	1 oz (28 g) Part-skim mozzarella cheese slices, halved	3 cups (430 g) Fresh strawberries, hulled and halved					Toast the English muffin halves until golden and crisp.	Heat the olive oil in a nonstick skillet over medium heat. Add the spinach and cook for 1 to 2 minutes until wilted.	Whisk the whole eggs, liquid egg whites, and black pepper in a small bowl. Pour into the skillet with the spinach and scramble for 2 to 3 minutes until mostly set.	Lay the tomato slices and halved mozzarella cheese slices directly over the eggs. Cover the skillet, remove from the heat, and let sit for 1 minute until the cheese melts.	Divide the egg and tomato scramble over the open-faced muffin halves.	Serve immediately with the fresh strawberries on the side.		Swap the strawberries for two cups of sliced fresh peaches.	Best enjoyed right away; does not keep.	417 kcal	25.7 g	9.6 g	45.0 g	16.7 g	4.4 g	17.8 g	0.0 g*	525 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Breakfast\IMG\open-faced_tomato_and_spinach_egg_melts.png
Pinto Bean and Avocado Breakfast Tostadas	Eating a combination of plant and egg protein in the morning helps maintain steady energy and lasting fullness until lunch.	10 min	11–16 min	1.5 tbsp (15 g) Raw pepitas	4 tortillas (100 g) Yellow corn tortillas	1 tsp (5 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1 1/2 cups (255 g) No-salt-added canned pinto beans, rinsed and drained	1 tsp (2 g) Ground cumin	4 cups (120 g) Baby spinach	2 large (100 g) Whole eggs	4 large (132 g) Egg whites	1/2 cup (110 g) Fresh pico de gallo	1/3 medium (50 g) Avocado, sliced				Place a large non-stick skillet over medium heat. Add the raw pepitas and toast for 2 to 3 minutes until golden and fragrant, then transfer to a small bowl.	Warm the corn tortillas in the same skillet over medium heat for 1 to 2 minutes per side until pliable and lightly toasted. Transfer to serving plates.	Add the extra-virgin olive oil, drained pinto beans, and ground cumin to the skillet over medium heat. Mash the beans roughly using a wooden spoon or silicone spatula for 3 to 4 minutes until warmed through, then divide evenly over the tortillas.	Add the baby spinach to the skillet and toss for 1 to 2 minutes until just wilted. Layer the spinach evenly over the mashed beans.	Whisk the whole eggs and egg whites together in a bowl. Pour into the skillet over medium-low heat and stir gently with a silicone spatula for 2 to 3 minutes until soft curds form and the eggs are set.	Spoon the scrambled eggs over the spinach. Top the tostadas evenly with the fresh pico de gallo, sliced avocado, and the toasted pepitas.		Swap the baby spinach for thinly sliced fresh Tuscan kale.	Best enjoyed right away; does not keep well once assembled.	527 kcal	32.9 g	18.7 g	64.0 g	17.6 g	3.5 g	3.2 g	0.0 g*	501 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Breakfast\IMG\pinto_bean_and_avocado_breakfast_tostadas.png	Savory Farro Breakfast Bowls with Eggs and Spinach	Starting your morning with intact grains and lean protein provides steady energy and lasting fullness. This single-skillet meal uses a convenient cooked grain pouch to keep prep time minimal.	5 min	7–10 min	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1.5 cups (225 g) Cherry tomatoes, halved	8.8 oz (250 g) Ready-to-eat cooked farro	3 cups (90 g) Fresh baby spinach	2 large (100 g) Whole eggs	1 cup (240 ml) Liquid egg whites	1/4 tsp (1.5 g) Salt	1/4 tsp (0.5 g) Black pepper	1/4 tsp (0.5 g) Crushed red pepper flakes	1 tbsp (15 ml) Fresh lemon juice	3 tbsp (30 g) Hemp hearts			Whisk the whole eggs and liquid egg whites together in a small bowl.	Heat the extra-virgin olive oil in a large skillet over medium heat. Add the cherry tomatoes and cook for 3 to 4 minutes until they blister and soften, checking at 3 minutes.	Break up the farro in its pouch, then add it to the skillet along with the spinach. Stir and cook for 1 to 2 minutes until the spinach wilts and the farro is warmed through.	Push the farro and vegetable mixture to the outer edges of the skillet to create an empty space in the center. Pour the egg mixture directly into the open space.	Cook the eggs for 3 to 4 minutes, stirring the center frequently with a spatula until softly scrambled and just set, checking at 3 minutes.	Remove the skillet from the heat. Fold the scrambled eggs into the farro mixture, then stir in the salt, black pepper, crushed red pepper flakes, and lemon juice.	Divide the mixture into serving bowls and sprinkle with the hemp hearts before serving.	Swap the fresh baby spinach for chopped Tuscan kale.	Keeps up to 2 days refrigerated; reheat gently in microwave.	486 kcal	32.9 g	8.1 g	46.9 g	20.7 g	3.4 g	4.6 g	0.0 g*	606 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Breakfast\IMG\savory_farro_breakfast_bowls_with_eggs_and_spinach.png
Savory Mediterranean Greek Yogurt Bowls	Starting your morning with a generous serving of lean protein and fiber helps maintain steady energy right through to lunch. This fresh, zero-cook bowl relies on artichokes and whole-wheat pita to deliver lasting fullness without weighing you down.	10 min	none (no-cook)	1 1/2 cups (340 g) Nonfat plain Greek yogurt	1 tbsp (15 ml) Lemon juice	1 cup (140 g) English cucumber, chopped	1 cup (150 g) Cherry tomatoes, halved	8 oz (225 g) Low-sodium canned artichoke hearts, rinsed, drained, and quartered	2 tsp (10 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	2 tbsp (18 g) Kalamata olives, pitted and minced	2 tbsp (18 g) Shelled pumpkin seeds (pepitas)	1 tsp (2 g) Dried oregano	2 pitas (120 g) 100% whole-wheat pita bread				Whisk the Greek yogurt and lemon juice together in a small bowl until completely smooth.	Spread the yogurt mixture evenly across the bottoms of two wide, shallow bowls.	Arrange the chopped cucumber, halved cherry tomatoes, and quartered artichoke hearts generously over the yogurt.	Drizzle the extra-virgin olive oil over the vegetables, then scatter the minced olives, pumpkin seeds, and dried oregano on top.	Toast the whole-wheat pitas in a toaster until slightly crisp and warm, then cut them into wedges.	Serve the bowls immediately with the warm pita wedges on the side for scooping.		Swap the whole-wheat pita for a side of cooked quinoa.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; toast the pita just before serving.	443 kcal	30.2 g	11.7 g	58.4 g	12.6 g	2.0 g	11.9 g	0.0 g*	477 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Breakfast\IMG\savory_mediterranean_greek_yogurt_bowls.png	Smoky Tomato Navy Beans and Eggs on Toast	Start your morning with this satisfying, single-pan savory skillet. It reimagines sugary baked beans as a fast, high-fiber dish that provides steady energy until lunch.	5 min	8–12 min	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	2 oz (56 g) Whole-wheat bread	2 tbsp (30 g) No-salt-added tomato paste	1 tsp (2 g) Smoked paprika	1 tsp (3 g) Garlic powder	9 oz (260 g) No-salt-added canned navy beans, rinsed and drained	1/4 cup (60 ml) Water	1 tbsp (15 ml) Apple cider vinegar	1/8 tsp (1 g) Salt	2 cups (60 g) Fresh baby spinach	4 large Large eggs			Heat the olive oil in a skillet over medium heat. Toast the whole-wheat bread in a toaster.	Add the tomato paste, smoked paprika, and garlic powder to the skillet. Stir constantly for 1 to 2 minutes until fragrant and slightly darkened.	Stir in the drained navy beans, water, apple cider vinegar, salt, and baby spinach. Simmer for 3 to 4 minutes until the spinach wilts and the liquid forms a thick sauce.	Push the bean mixture aside to create wide wells in the skillet. Crack the eggs into the wells.	Cover the skillet and cook for 4 to 6 minutes. Check at 4 minutes to ensure the egg whites are completely set and the yolks remain soft.	Divide the toasted bread between plates. Scoop the eggs and smoky beans over the top to serve.		Swap the navy beans for no-salt-added canned cannellini beans.	Best enjoyed right away; cooked eggs and toast do not keep.	495 kcal	28.5 g	17.1 g	52.4 g	19.6 g	4.6 g	4.0 g	0.0 g*	486 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Breakfast\IMG\smoky_tomato_navy_beans_and_eggs_on_toast.png
Smoky White Bean and Broccoli Skillet Frittata	This simple skillet breakfast requires minimal prep and moves quickly from the stovetop to the oven. Folding white beans into a mix of eggs and broccoli creates a filling base that pairs well with fresh oranges.	10 min	13–18 min	2 tsp (10 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1/2 cup (80 g) Red onion, diced	1 1/2 cups (130 g) Frozen chopped broccoli	9 oz (260 g) No-salt-added canned navy beans, rinsed and drained	2 large (100 g) Whole eggs	1 cup (240 g) Liquid egg whites	1 tsp (2 g) Smoked paprika	1/4 tsp (1 g) Black pepper	1/2 oz (14 g) Sharp cheddar cheese, shredded	2 medium (260 g) Fresh oranges, peeled and segmented				Preheat the oven to 400°F / 200°C. Whisk the whole eggs, liquid egg whites, smoked paprika, and black pepper in a medium bowl until combined.	Heat the olive oil in an oven-safe skillet over medium heat.	Add the red onion to the skillet and cook until softened, 3 to 4 minutes, checking at 3 minutes.	Stir in the frozen broccoli and drained navy beans. Cook until warmed through, 2 to 3 minutes, checking at 2 minutes.	Pour the egg mixture over the vegetables in the skillet. Cook undisturbed on medium-low heat until the edges begin to set, 3 to 4 minutes, checking at 3 minutes.	Sprinkle the cheddar cheese over the top and transfer the skillet to the oven. Bake until the center sets, 5 to 7 minutes, checking at 5 minutes.	Remove the skillet from the oven using an oven mitt. Slice the frittata in half and serve warm with the fresh orange segments.	Swap the cheddar cheese for crumbled feta or goat cheese.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; reheat briefly in the microwave.	453 kcal	34.4 g	13.1 g	51.1 g	13.4 g	3.8 g	16.9 g	0.0 g*	345 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Breakfast\IMG\smoky_white_bean_and_broccoli_skillet_frittata.png	Southwestern Tempeh and Pepper Breakfast Scramble	This energizing breakfast replaces eggs with hearty crumbled tempeh to keep you full well past mid-morning. Smoky cumin and paprika bring bold Southwestern flavor to the skillet without relying on heavy sauces.	10 min	8–11 min	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	6 oz (170 g) Frozen bell pepper and onion blend	9 oz (255 g) Original tempeh, crumbled	1 tsp (2 g) Ground cumin	1/2 tsp (1 g) Smoked paprika	4 oz (113 g) Cherry tomatoes, halved	3 oz (85 g) 100% whole-wheat tortillas	2 oz (57 g) Hass avocado, diced	1/4 cup (4 g) Fresh cilantro, chopped					Heat the olive oil in a large nonstick skillet over medium heat until shimmering.	Add the frozen pepper and onion blend. Cook for 3 to 4 minutes, stirring occasionally, until softened and any ice has evaporated.	Stir in the crumbled tempeh, ground cumin, and smoked paprika. Cook for 4 to 5 minutes until the tempeh is browned and aromatic.	Fold in the halved cherry tomatoes. Cook for 1 to 2 minutes until they begin to soften.	Warm the whole-wheat tortillas in a dry skillet or microwave until pliable.	Divide the tempeh scramble between plates. Top with the diced avocado and chopped cilantro, and serve alongside the warm tortillas.		Swap the cherry tomatoes for a handful of baby spinach.	Keeps 2-3 days refrigerated; reheat in a skillet over medium.	517 kcal	32.3 g	8.4 g	38.4 g	29.7 g	7.0 g	2.8 g	0.0 g*	286 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Breakfast\IMG\southwestern_tempeh_and_pepper_breakfast_scramble.png
Tex-Mex Sweet Potato and Black Bean Breakfast Scramble	Smoky cumin and vibrant salsa deliver bold southwestern flavor to this protein-packed, vegetable-forward breakfast. Pairing convenient frozen sweet potatoes with pantry black beans creates a hearty, high-fiber foundation that helps prevent mid-morning energy crashes.	5 min	9–12 min	1 tsp (5 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	7 oz (200 g) Frozen diced sweet potatoes	1 tsp (2 g) Ground cumin	1 cup (260 g) No-salt-added canned black beans, rinsed and drained	10 oz (300 g) Liquid egg whites	2 large (100 g) Whole eggs	1/4 cup (60 ml) Mild chunky salsa	2.5 oz (75 g) Avocado, diced	1/4 cup (10 g) Fresh cilantro, chopped					Whisk the liquid egg whites and whole eggs together in a bowl until uniformly smooth.	Heat a large nonstick skillet over medium-high heat with the olive oil until the oil shimmers.	Add the sweet potatoes and cook, stirring occasionally, until tender and browned at the edges, 6 to 8 minutes. Check at 6 minutes.	Reduce the burner to medium. Stir the cumin and black beans into the skillet, tossing gently until the beans are warmed through.	Pour the egg mixture over the vegetables. Cook gently, pushing the eggs across the bottom with a silicone spatula as they begin to set, until fully cooked but still soft, 3 to 4 minutes. Check at 3 minutes.	Remove the skillet from the heat.	Divide the scramble between two plates and top evenly with the salsa, avocado, and cilantro before serving.	Swap the black beans for rinsed, no-salt-added pinto beans.	Best enjoyed right away; does not keep.	457 kcal	33.7 g	14.0 g	51.0 g	13.6 g	2.8 g	3.1 g	0.0 g*	725 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Breakfast\IMG\tex-mex_sweet_potato_and_black_bean_breakfast_scramble.png	Warm Blueberry and Vanilla Skyr Waffles	Packing plenty of protein and fiber, this comforting breakfast helps keep your morning energy steady until lunch. Tangy Skyr and warm berries replace sugary syrup for a naturally sweet start.	5 min	4–5 min	4 waffles (140 g) Frozen 100% whole-wheat waffles	1 1/2 cups (210 g) Frozen blueberries	2 cups (454 g) Nonfat plain Skyr	1 tsp (4 ml) Pure vanilla extract	1/2 tsp (1 g) Ground cinnamon	3 tbsp (30 g) Hemp hearts	1/4 cup (28 g) Chopped walnuts							Toast the whole-wheat waffles in a toaster or oven according to the package directions until golden and crisp.	Place the frozen blueberries in a small saucepan over medium heat while the waffles toast.	Cook the blueberries, stirring occasionally, for 4 to 5 minutes until the berries soften and burst. Remove the saucepan from the heat.	Whisk the Skyr, vanilla extract, and ground cinnamon in a medium bowl until smooth.	Divide the warm toasted waffles between two plates.	Spoon the vanilla Skyr mixture over the waffles, then ladle the warm blueberry sauce on top.	Sprinkle the hemp hearts and chopped walnuts over the waffles before serving.	Swap the chopped walnuts for sliced almonds or toasted pecans.	Best enjoyed right away; does not keep.	549 kcal	35.5 g	7.6 g	59.2 g	20.5 g	2.4 g	20.1 g	0.0 g*	474 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Breakfast\IMG\warm_blueberry_and_vanilla_skyr_waffles.png
