Title_1	Introduction_1	Preparation_time_1	Cooking_1	Ingredient_1_1	Ingredient_2_1	Ingredient_3_1	Ingredient_4_1	Ingredient_5_1	Ingredient_6_1	Ingredient_7_1	Ingredient_8_1	Ingredient_9_1	Ingredient_10_1	Ingredient_11_1	Ingredient_12_1	Ingredient_13_1	Instruction_1_1	Instruction_2_1	Instruction_3_1	Instruction_4_1	Instruction_5_1	Instruction_6_1	Instruction_7_1	Variation_1	Storage_1	Calories_1	Protein_1	Fiber_1	Carbs_1	TotalFat_1	SaturatedFat_1	TotalSugars_1	AddedSugars_1	Sodium_1	@Image_1	Title_2	Introduction_2	Preparation_time_2	Cooking_2	Ingredient_1_2	Ingredient_2_2	Ingredient_3_2	Ingredient_4_2	Ingredient_5_2	Ingredient_6_2	Ingredient_7_2	Ingredient_8_2	Ingredient_9_2	Ingredient_10_2	Ingredient_11_2	Ingredient_12_2	Ingredient_13_2	Instruction_1_2	Instruction_2_2	Instruction_3_2	Instruction_4_2	Instruction_5_2	Instruction_6_2	Instruction_7_2	Variation_2	Storage_2	Calories_2	Protein_2	Fiber_2	Carbs_2	TotalFat_2	SaturatedFat_2	TotalSugars_2	AddedSugars_2	Sodium_2	@Image_2
Almond Butter and Cocoa Stuffed Dates	Relying on whole fruit for sweetness provides steady energy without a sugar crash. These Medjool dates deliver a rich chocolate center alongside satisfying fiber and lean protein.	10 min	none (no-cook)	2 large (48 g) Medjool dates, pitted and halved lengthwise	2 tbsp (32 g) Natural almond butter	2 tsp (4 g) Unsweetened cocoa powder	1/2 tsp (2 ml) Vanilla extract	2 tbsp (14 g) Chopped walnuts, chopped	1/8 tsp (0.5 g) Flaky sea salt								Arrange the date halves cut-side up on a small plate. Press the centers to widen the cavities.	Mix the almond butter, cocoa powder, and vanilla extract in a small bowl until the ingredients form a thick paste.	Divide the almond-cocoa mixture evenly among the date halves. Press the filling into the hollowed centers.	Sprinkle the chopped walnuts over the filled dates. Press the nuts into the almond butter so they stick.	Top each piece with flaky sea salt before serving.			Swap the chopped walnuts for raw unsalted pumpkin seeds.	Keeps 4 to 5 days refrigerated in an airtight container.	218 kcal	5.2 g	4.5 g	23.2 g	13.8 g	1.3 g	17.0 g	0.0 g*	99 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dessert\IMG\almond_butter_and_cocoa_stuffed_dates.png	Baked Cinnamon Apple Slices with Vanilla Greek Yogurt	This incredibly simple, fast-prep dessert requires almost no active time. Warm, spice-roasted apples deliver comforting flavor over a protein-rich base of vanilla Greek yogurt.	10 min	15–20 min	9 oz (250 g) Fresh apple, cored and sliced 1/4-inch thick	1 tsp (2 g) Ground cinnamon	1/4 tsp (0.5 g) Ground nutmeg	1 tsp (5 ml) Maple syrup	5.5 oz (150 g) Nonfat plain Greek yogurt	1 tsp (5 ml) Vanilla extract	2 tbsp (15 g) Pecans, chopped							Preheat the oven to 400°F / 200°C. Line a baking sheet with parchment paper.	Toss the sliced apples with the cinnamon, nutmeg, and maple syrup in a bowl until evenly coated.	Spread the apples in a single layer on the prepared baking sheet.	Bake for 15 to 20 minutes, or until the apples are tender and lightly browned. Check at 15 minutes.	Stir the vanilla extract into the Greek yogurt while the apples bake.	Divide the vanilla yogurt between two small bowls and top warmly with the baked apple slices.	Sprinkle the chopped pecans over the apples and serve immediately.	Swap the chopped pecans for sliced almonds or toasted walnuts.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; reheat apples slightly before serving.	191 kcal	8.6 g	3.9 g	25.8 g	6.0 g	0.6 g	19.3 g	2.4 g*	28 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dessert\IMG\baked_cinnamon_apple_slices_with_vanilla_greek_yogurt.png
Broiled Cinnamon Peaches with Vanilla Ricotta Cream	With minimal prep, this warm dessert is ready in under 15 minutes. Broiling fresh peaches concentrates their natural juices, pairing well with the vanilla ricotta and crunchy almonds.	10 min	5–7 min	10.5 oz (300 g) Fresh peaches, halved and pitted	1/4 cup (60 g) Part-skim ricotta cheese	1 tsp (5 ml) Vanilla extract	1/2 tsp (1 g) Ground cinnamon	2 tbsp (15 g) Sliced almonds	2 tsp (10 ml) Pure maple syrup								Preheat the oven broiler to High (500°F / 260°C) for 3 minutes. Line a baking sheet with foil.	Place the peaches cut-side up on the prepared baking sheet. Dust evenly with the cinnamon.	Broil for 5 to 7 minutes, checking at 5 minutes, until the fruit is tender and the edges are lightly golden.	Whisk the ricotta cheese and vanilla extract in a bowl until smooth and creamy.	Toast the sliced almonds in a dry skillet over medium heat for 2 to 3 minutes, shaking the pan frequently, until lightly browned and fragrant.	Divide the warm peaches between serving plates. Top each half with the vanilla ricotta, maple syrup, and toasted almonds.		Swap the fresh peaches for halved and cored fresh plums.	Best enjoyed right away; does not keep.	166 kcal	6.4 g	3.3 g	21.5 g	6.7 g	1.8 g	16.4 g	3.4 g*	31 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dessert\IMG\broiled_cinnamon_peaches_with_vanilla_ricotta_cream.png	Cardamom-Poached Pears with Pistachio Yogurt	Swapping heavy wine syrups for an aromatic poaching liquid lets the true flavor of the fruit shine. Paired with thick yogurt, it creates an elegant, blood-sugar-friendly finish to any meal.	10 min	10–12 min	2 small (260 g) Firm pears, peeled, halved lengthwise, and cored	1/2 cup (120 ml) Water	1 stick (2 g) Cinnamon stick	3 pods (1 g) Cardamom pods, lightly crushed	2 wide strips (4 g) Orange peel	1/2 cup (115 g) Nonfat plain Greek yogurt	2 tsp (10 ml) Pure maple syrup	1 tsp (5 ml) Vanilla extract	1 tbsp (8 g) Shelled pistachios, roughly chopped					Combine the water, cinnamon stick, cardamom pods, and orange peel in a small saucepan and bring to a rolling boil over medium-high heat.	Reduce the heat to medium-low and add the pear halves to the saucepan, cut-side down.	Cover with a lid and simmer for 10 to 12 minutes until the pears are tender when pierced with a fork.	Whisk the Greek yogurt, maple syrup, and vanilla extract in a small bowl until smooth while the pears poach.	Remove the saucepan from the heat and transfer the poached pears to a plate to cool.	Divide the sweetened yogurt between shallow bowls and spread it into an even layer.	Arrange the warm pear halves over the yogurt in each bowl and sprinkle with the chopped pistachios before serving.	Swap the pistachios for toasted slivered almonds or chopped walnuts.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated. Reheat pears gently in the microwave.	157 kcal	7.3 g	5.3 g	28.3 g	2.3 g	0.3 g	18.2 g	3.0 g*	26 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dessert\IMG\cardamom-poached_pears_with_pistachio_yogurt.png
Chocolate Peanut Butter Banana Nice Cream	This frozen treat delivers the thick texture of soft-serve ice cream using simple everyday staples. It satisfies sweet cravings naturally with whole fruit, rich cocoa, and a steady supply of protein.	5 min	none (no-cook)	5.3 oz (150 g) Frozen bananas, frozen and sliced	1/3 cup (75 g) Nonfat plain Greek yogurt	2 tbsp (30 ml) Unsweetened almond milk	1 tbsp (16 g) Natural creamy peanut butter	1 tbsp (5 g) Unsweetened cocoa powder	1/2 tsp (2 ml) Vanilla extract	2 tsp (10 g) Dark chocolate chips							Place the frozen banana slices, Greek yogurt, almond milk, peanut butter, cocoa powder, and vanilla extract into a food processor or blender.	Pulse the ingredients to break down the frozen fruit, then blend on high speed.	Stop the machine and scrape down the sides with a rubber spatula to integrate the ingredients.	Blend until the mixture is smooth, thick, and resembles soft-serve ice cream.	Divide the mixture evenly between two serving bowls.	Sprinkle the dark chocolate chips over the top of each bowl.	Serve immediately while chilled.	Swap the peanut butter for natural almond butter.	Best enjoyed right away; does not keep.	175 kcal	7.3 g	3.6 g	25.0 g	6.6 g	2.1 g	13.8 g	2.3 g*	61 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dessert\IMG\chocolate_peanut_butter_banana_nice_cream.png	Raspberry and Vanilla Yogurt Chia Pudding	This refreshing make-ahead dessert is ready in the fridge whenever you need a creamy treat. Chia seeds and Greek yogurt create a spoonable base layered with bright berries.	5 min	none (no-cook)	3 tbsp (30 g) Chia seeds	3/4 cup (180 ml) Unsweetened soy milk	1/2 cup (115 g) Plain nonfat Greek yogurt	2 tsp (10 ml) Pure maple syrup	1/2 tsp (2 ml) Vanilla extract	1 cup (120 g) Fresh raspberries, rinsed and dried	1 tbsp (8 g) Sliced almonds							Whisk the chia seeds, soy milk, Greek yogurt, maple syrup, and vanilla extract together in a medium bowl until smooth.	Let the mixture sit for 5 minutes, then whisk it again to prevent the seeds from clumping.	Cover the bowl and refrigerate for at least 2 hours or overnight to allow the chia seeds to hydrate.	Divide the thickened pudding between serving glasses or bowls.	Top the pudding with the raspberries and sliced almonds before serving.			Swap the fresh raspberries for diced fresh peaches or strawberries.	Keeps up to 3 days in an airtight container refrigerated.	213 kcal	12.3 g	10.1 g	24.7 g	8.0 g	0.8 g	9.6 g	4.2 g*	81 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dessert\IMG\raspberry_and_vanilla_yogurt_chia_pudding.png
Sea Salt Dark Chocolate and Apricot Clusters	When you want a satisfying after-dinner treat or an afternoon pick-me-up, these bites deliver a candy-like experience without the sugar crash. Dried fruit and crunchy nuts bind together with dark chocolate to create a perfect salty-sweet balance.	10 min	none (no-cook)	2 oz (55 g) Unsweetened dried apricots, finely chopped	2 tbsp (20 g) Dry-roasted unsalted almonds, roughly chopped	1 tbsp (10 g) Dry-roasted pumpkin seeds	1 tbsp (12 g) Dark chocolate chips (70% cocoa or higher)	1/8 tsp (0.5 g) Flaky sea salt									Line a small plate or baking sheet with parchment paper.	Combine the finely chopped apricots, almonds, and pumpkin seeds in a small bowl and toss to mix.	Place the dark chocolate chips in a small microwave-safe bowl and microwave on high in 15-second bursts, stirring between each, until completely smooth.	Pour the melted chocolate over the apricot and nut mixture, stirring until all pieces are coated.	Scoop the mixture into clusters on the prepared plate and press them with the back of a spoon so they hold together.	Sprinkle the clusters evenly with the flaky sea salt.	Place the plate in the freezer to set until firm, about 10 to 15 minutes.	Swap the dried apricots for unsweetened dried cherries or figs.	Keeps 1 week refrigerated in an airtight container.	191 kcal	5.0 g	4.1 g	22.8 g	10.4 g	2.3 g	16.7 g	1.4 g*	102 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dessert\IMG\sea_salt_dark_chocolate_and_apricot_clusters.png	Warm Berry and Almond Skillet Crisp	For a cozy weeknight dessert, this quick stovetop crumble hits all the right comfort notes. Lightly toasting the oats and nuts adds a satisfying crunch over tangy Greek yogurt and naturally sweet fruit.	5 min	7–11 min	6 1/2 oz (180 g) Frozen mixed berries	3/4 oz (20 g) Old-fashioned rolled oats	3/4 oz (20 g) Sliced almonds	1/2 tbsp (7 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1 tsp (2 g) Ground cinnamon	1 tsp (5 ml) Pure maple syrup	1/2 tsp (2.5 ml) Pure vanilla extract	4 1/4 oz (120 g) Nonfat plain Greek yogurt						Combine the oats, almonds, and extra-virgin olive oil in a small skillet over medium heat.	Toast the mixture for 4 to 6 minutes, stirring frequently, until the oats are golden and fragrant. Transfer the oat mixture to a small bowl and set aside.	Return the skillet to medium heat and add the frozen berries, cinnamon, and maple syrup. Simmer for 3 to 5 minutes, mashing slightly with a spoon, until the fruit softens and the juices begin to bubble and thicken. Check at 3 minutes.	Remove the skillet from the heat and stir the vanilla extract directly into the warm berries.	Divide the Greek yogurt between two serving bowls, spoon the warm fruit over the yogurt, and top evenly with the toasted crisp mixture.			Swap the sliced almonds for chopped pecans or walnuts.	Best enjoyed right away; the crisp topping does not keep.	214 kcal	10.2 g	4.6 g	22.7 g	9.6 g	1.1 g	9.8 g	1.5 g*	23 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dessert\IMG\warm_berry_and_almond_skillet_crisp.png
Warm Lemon Custard with Fresh Raspberries	This remarkably easy dessert relies on a brief stovetop technique to build a luxurious texture with minimal effort. You will whisk low-fat milk, an egg, and a touch of cornstarch into a warm, creamy base before topping it with fresh raspberries.	5 min	4–6 min	1 1/4 cups (305 g) Low-fat milk (1%)	1 large (50 g) Large egg	1 tbsp (15 ml) Pure maple syrup	1 tbsp (8 g) Cornstarch	1 tsp (2 g) Lemon zest, finely grated	1 tsp (5 ml) Pure vanilla extract	1 cup (123 g) Fresh raspberries							In a medium saucepan, vigorously whisk the milk, egg, maple syrup, and cornstarch off the heat until entirely smooth.	Place the saucepan on the stovetop over medium heat.	Whisk constantly for 4 to 6 minutes, until the mixture begins to gently bubble and significantly thickens into a pudding-like consistency. Check at 4 minutes.	Remove the saucepan from the heat immediately.	Stir in the finely grated lemon zest and vanilla extract.	Divide the warm custard evenly between two serving bowls and top with the fresh raspberries.		Swap the raspberries for sliced fresh strawberries or whole blackberries.	Keeps 2-3 days refrigerated; enjoy cold or gently reheat.	179 kcal	9.1 g	4.1 g	25.9 g	4.3 g	1.7 g	16.8 g	6.0 g*	105 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dessert\IMG\warm_lemon_custard_with_fresh_raspberries.png	Warm Pumpkin Spice Oat Mug Cakes	This simple dessert requires minimal prep and uses the microwave to bake quickly. Canned pure pumpkin and oat flour create a cozy, spiced cake topped with cool Greek yogurt.	5 min	2–4 min	1/3 cup (80 g) Canned pure pumpkin	1 (50 g) Large egg	1 tbsp (15 ml) Pure maple syrup	1 tsp (5 ml) Vanilla extract	1/3 cup (32 g) Oat flour	1 tsp (2 g) Pumpkin pie spice	1/2 tsp (2 g) Baking powder	1 tbsp (8 g) Chopped pecans, finely chopped	1/4 cup (60 g) Nonfat plain Greek yogurt					Whisk the pumpkin, egg, maple syrup, and vanilla extract in a small bowl until completely smooth.	Stir the oat flour, pumpkin pie spice, and baking powder into the wet ingredients until just combined into a thick batter.	Divide the batter evenly between two microwave-safe mugs or small ramekins.	Microwave one mug on high power for 1 to 2 minutes, checking at 1 minute, until the cake is puffed and the center is set.	Repeat the microwave process with the second mug, then let both rest.	Top each warm cake with the Greek yogurt and pecans before serving.		Swap the chopped pecans for finely chopped walnuts.	Best enjoyed right away; does not keep.	194 kcal	9.2 g	3.4 g	24.2 g	6.6 g	1.2 g	9.0 g	6.0 g*	157 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dessert\IMG\warm_pumpkin_spice_oat_mug_cakes.png
