Title_1	Introduction_1	Preparation_time_1	Cooking_1	Ingredient_1_1	Ingredient_2_1	Ingredient_3_1	Ingredient_4_1	Ingredient_5_1	Ingredient_6_1	Ingredient_7_1	Ingredient_8_1	Ingredient_9_1	Ingredient_10_1	Ingredient_11_1	Ingredient_12_1	Ingredient_13_1	Instruction_1_1	Instruction_2_1	Instruction_3_1	Instruction_4_1	Instruction_5_1	Instruction_6_1	Instruction_7_1	Variation_1	Storage_1	Calories_1	Protein_1	Fiber_1	Carbs_1	TotalFat_1	SaturatedFat_1	TotalSugars_1	AddedSugars_1	Sodium_1	@Image_1	Title_2	Introduction_2	Preparation_time_2	Cooking_2	Ingredient_1_2	Ingredient_2_2	Ingredient_3_2	Ingredient_4_2	Ingredient_5_2	Ingredient_6_2	Ingredient_7_2	Ingredient_8_2	Ingredient_9_2	Ingredient_10_2	Ingredient_11_2	Ingredient_12_2	Ingredient_13_2	Instruction_1_2	Instruction_2_2	Instruction_3_2	Instruction_4_2	Instruction_5_2	Instruction_6_2	Instruction_7_2	Variation_2	Storage_2	Calories_2	Protein_2	Fiber_2	Carbs_2	TotalFat_2	SaturatedFat_2	TotalSugars_2	AddedSugars_2	Sodium_2	@Image_2
Balsamic-Mustard Pork Medallions with Asparagus and Couscous	Building a pan sauce from tangy mustard and balsamic vinegar gives this skillet dinner deep flavor without excess saturated fat. Slicing a lean pork tenderloin into quick-cooking medallions keeps the meat tender and speeds up weeknight prep.	10 min	12–16 min	3/4 cup (130 g) Whole wheat couscous, dry	3/4 cup (180 ml) Water, boiling	12 oz (340 g) Pork tenderloin, cut into 1-inch thick medallions	1/2 tsp (1.5 g) Garlic powder	1/2 tsp (0.5 g) Dried thyme	1/4 tsp (0.5 g) Black pepper	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	10 oz (280 g) Asparagus, tough ends snapped off, cut into 2-inch pieces	1/2 cup (120 ml) Low-sodium chicken broth	2 tbsp (30 ml) Balsamic vinegar	1 tbsp (15 g) Dijon mustard			Combine the dry couscous and boiling water in a heatproof bowl. Cover tightly and set aside to steam.	Season the pork medallions evenly with the garlic powder, dried thyme, and black pepper.	Heat the olive oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat. Add the seasoned pork and cook for 6 to 8 minutes, flipping halfway, before transferring to a plate.	Place the asparagus pieces into the same skillet over medium heat. Cook for 4 to 5 minutes, tossing occasionally, until tender-crisp, then transfer to the plate with the pork.	Lower the heat to medium-low and whisk the chicken broth, balsamic vinegar, and Dijon mustard into the skillet, scraping up any browned bits from the bottom.	Simmer the liquid for 2 to 3 minutes until slightly thickened into a pan sauce. Return the pork and asparagus to the skillet, turning them to coat evenly.	Fluff the steeped couscous with a fork and divide it between plates. Top with the glazed pork, asparagus, and any remaining pan sauce.	Swap the asparagus for fresh green beans.	Keeps 3 days refrigerated; reheat gently on the stovetop.	545 kcal	48.7 g	6.7 g	57.9 g	12.4 g	2.5 g	2.9 g	0.0 g*	205 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\balsamic-mustard_pork_medallions_with_asparagus_and_couscous.png	Balsamic-Seared Mahi-Mahi with Tomato-Lentil Quinoa	Tangy balsamic vinegar creates a rich glaze over flaky seared fish and sweet blistered cherry tomatoes. Using a ready-to-eat quinoa pouch and canned lentils builds a high-fiber base without the wait.	10 min	11–16 min	9 oz (255 g) Mahi-Mahi fillets, thawed if frozen, patted dry	1 tsp (3 g) Garlic powder	1 tsp (1 g) Dried oregano	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1 1/2 cups (225 g) Cherry tomatoes, whole	2 tbsp (30 ml) Balsamic vinegar	1 cup (200 g) No-salt-added canned brown lentils, rinsed and drained	1 cup (185 g) Ready-to-eat cooked quinoa	2 cups (60 g) Baby spinach, loosely packed					Pat the fish fillets dry and season on both sides with the garlic powder, dried oregano, and black pepper.	Heat the olive oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat. Add the fish and sear for 3 to 4 minutes, flip at the halfway point, and cook for another 3 to 4 minutes until opaque, then transfer to a plate and cover.	Reduce the heat to medium and add the cherry tomatoes to the skillet. Cook for 4 to 5 minutes, stirring occasionally, until the tomatoes blister and begin to burst.	Pour the balsamic vinegar into the skillet and stir constantly to scrape up any browned bits from the bottom. Simmer for 1 to 2 minutes to reduce the liquid.	Stir the lentils and quinoa into the skillet to combine with the pan juices. Cook for 2 to 3 minutes until completely heated through.	Fold in the baby spinach and toss gently for 1 to 2 minutes. Remove the skillet from the heat as soon as the leaves wilt.	Divide the warm lentil and quinoa mixture between shallow bowls. Top with a seared fillet and spoon the remaining pan juices over the fish.	Swap the mahi-mahi fillets for firm white cod or tilapia.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; reheat gently on the stovetop.	433 kcal	38.8 g	12.7 g	46.5 g	10.5 g	1.5 g	5.7 g	0.0 g*	162 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\balsamic-seared_mahi-mahi_with_tomato-lentil_quinoa.png
Beef and Lentil Meatballs with Zucchini and Quinoa	Tender, herbaceous meatballs simmer in a rich tomato base for a deeply savory and comforting meal. Mashing brown lentils directly into the lean beef mixture lowers the saturated fat while keeping the texture soft and boosting the fiber.	10 min	14–18 min	1/2 cup (100 g) No-salt-added canned brown lentils, rinsed and drained	8 oz (225 g) Extra-lean ground beef (96% lean)	1 tsp (3 g) Garlic powder	1 tsp (1 g) Dried oregano	1/4 tsp (1.5 g) Salt	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1 medium (200 g) Zucchini, diced	1 cup (240 g) No-salt-added crushed tomatoes	1 cup (200 g) Ready-to-eat cooked quinoa pouch	1/4 cup (15 g) Fresh parsley, chopped				Place the drained lentils in a mixing bowl and mash them roughly with a fork.	Add the ground beef, garlic powder, dried oregano, salt, and half the fresh parsley to the bowl. Mix gently with your hands to combine, then roll the mixture into evenly sized meatballs.	Warm the olive oil in a large skillet over medium heat until shimmering. Add the meatballs and cook for 4 to 5 minutes, turning occasionally, until browned on all sides.	Add the diced zucchini to the skillet and cook for 2 to 3 minutes, stirring occasionally, until the zucchini begins to soften.	Pour the crushed tomatoes over the meatballs and zucchini. Bring the mixture to a gentle simmer.	Cover the skillet, reduce the heat to medium-low, and simmer for 8 to 10 minutes. Check the meatballs at 8 minutes to ensure they are no longer pink in the center.	Warm the quinoa pouch in the microwave while the skillet finishes simmering. Divide the quinoa between plates, top with the meatballs and sauce, and garnish with the remaining fresh parsley.	Swap the diced zucchini for chopped yellow bell pepper.	Keeps 3 days refrigerated; reheat gently in the microwave.	458 kcal	36.6 g	10.6 g	45.1 g	15.5 g	3.8 g	9.7 g	0.0 g*	404 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\beef_and_lentil_meatballs_with_zucchini_and_quinoa.png	Beef and Spinach Stuffed Portobellos with Quinoa	Using large portobello caps as edible roasting vessels traps the savory juices of the filling, transforming an everyday ground beef skillet into a simple centerpiece. Serve these mushrooms alongside warm quinoa to soak up every drop of flavor.	10 min	10–15 min	4 large caps (340 g) Portobello mushroom caps, wiped clean, stems removed	2 tsp (10 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil, divided	8 oz (225 g) Extra-lean ground beef (96% lean)	2 cloves (6 g) Garlic, minced	4 cups (120 g) Baby spinach	1/2 cup (120 g) No-salt-added diced tomatoes, drained	1 tsp (1 g) Dried oregano	1/4 tsp (1 g) Kosher salt	2 tbsp (14 g) Feta cheese, crumbled	1 pouch (8.8 oz / 250 g) Ready-to-eat cooked quinoa				Preheat the oven to 400°F / 200°C. Place the mushroom caps gill-side up on a baking sheet, brush with olive oil, and bake for 10 to 12 minutes until tender.	Heat olive oil in a skillet over medium-high heat until shimmering. Add the ground beef, minced garlic, and kosher salt.	Break the meat apart with a spoon and cook for 4 to 5 minutes until browned.	Stir the spinach, diced tomatoes, and dried oregano into the skillet. Cook for 2 to 3 minutes until the spinach is fully wilted.	Warm the quinoa pouch in the microwave according to the package instructions.	Remove the mushrooms from the oven and carefully drain any excess liquid that pooled inside the caps.	Spoon the hot beef and spinach mixture into the mushroom caps. Top with the crumbled feta and serve alongside the warm quinoa.	Swap the ground beef for extra-lean ground turkey breast.	Keeps 3 days refrigerated; reheat in the oven or microwave.	432 kcal	36.6 g	8.1 g	38.3 g	15.7 g	4.4 g	6.9 g	0.0 g*	445 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\beef_and_spinach_stuffed_portobellos_with_quinoa.png
Broiled Walnut-Mustard Salmon with Asparagus	Perfect for a quick weeknight dinner, this meal uses the broiler to cook everything on a single pan. The crunchy walnut coating provides omega-3s while keeping the fish tender.	10 min	6–8 min	16 oz (450 g) Fresh asparagus, woody ends trimmed	2 tsp (10 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1/4 tsp (1.5 g) Salt	1/2 tsp (1 g) Black pepper	8 oz (225 g) Fresh salmon fillets, cut into two portions	1 tbsp (15 g) Whole-grain mustard	1 tbsp (15 ml) Fresh lemon juice	3 tbsp (20 g) Walnuts, finely chopped	8.8 oz (250 g) Ready-to-eat cooked brown rice pouch					Preheat the broiler to high (500°F / 260°C) with a rack in the upper third of the oven. Line a rimmed baking sheet with foil.	Toss the trimmed asparagus directly on the baking sheet with the olive oil, half the salt, and half the pepper. Push the asparagus to one side of the pan.	Place the salmon fillets on the empty side of the baking sheet. Mix the mustard and lemon juice in a small bowl, then spread the mixture evenly over the top of the salmon.	Press the chopped walnuts into the mustard layer on each fillet. Sprinkle the remaining salt and pepper over the fish.	Broil for 6 to 8 minutes until the asparagus is tender, the walnuts are toasted, and the salmon flakes easily with a fork. Check the pan at 6 minutes to ensure the nuts do not burn.	Heat the brown rice pouch in the microwave according to the package instructions while the fish cooks.	Divide the warm brown rice, roasted asparagus, and walnut-crusted salmon evenly between two plates.	Swap the asparagus spears for fresh trimmed green beans.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; reheat gently in the microwave.	528 kcal	33.3 g	7.9 g	43.3 g	25.8 g	4.5 g	5.1 g	0.0 g*	454 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\broiled_walnut-mustard_salmon_with_asparagus.png	Chili-Lime Cod Tacos with Black Beans and Slaw	Zesty, bright, and deeply savory, these pan-seared cod tacos offer the crisp textures of taco night without deep-frying. The black beans build a high-fiber carbohydrate base that helps provide steady energy.	10 min	10–13 min	1 1/2 cups Pre-shredded red cabbage	1/4 cup Fresh cilantro, chopped	2 tbsp (30 ml) Fresh lime juice, divided	1/2 medium Avocado, diced	10 oz (285 g) Untreated fresh or frozen cod fillets, thawed if frozen	1 tsp (2 g) Chili powder	1/8 tsp (0.75 g) Salt	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1 cup (260 g) No-salt-added canned black beans, rinsed and drained	4 tortillas Corn tortillas				Toss the cabbage, cilantro, half the lime juice, and the avocado in a medium bowl. Mash the avocado into the greens to dress the slaw, then set aside.	Pat the cod dry with a paper towel. Season on all sides with the chili powder and salt.	Heat the olive oil in a large nonstick skillet over medium-high heat. Add the cod and cook for 3 to 4 minutes per side, flipping halfway, until golden and opaque.	Transfer the cod to a clean plate and flake it into bite-sized pieces with a fork. Drizzle the remaining lime juice over the flaked fish.	Reduce the stovetop heat to medium and add the rinsed black beans to the same skillet. Stir frequently for 2 to 3 minutes until warmed through, then transfer to a serving bowl.	Wipe out the skillet and place it over medium-high heat. Warm the corn tortillas for 30 seconds per side, flipping halfway, until soft and pliable.	Divide the warm tortillas between two plates and fill with the flaked cod. Top with the avocado slaw and serve the warm black beans alongside.	Swap the cod fillets for untreated, peeled medium shrimp.	Best enjoyed right away; does not keep well.	490 kcal	37.8 g	16.0 g	52.5 g	15.6 g	2.3 g	3.3 g	0.0 g*	471 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\chili-lime_cod_tacos_with_black_beans_and_slaw.png
Creamy Dijon Mushroom and Lentils Over Farro	Trading heavy cream and beef for nonfat Greek yogurt and lentils turns a classic stroganoff into a satisfying weekday dinner. This earthy dish delivers a comforting tang alongside plenty of plant-based protein and fiber.	10 min	8–11 min	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	8 oz (225 g) Cremini mushrooms, sliced	2 cloves (6 g) Garlic, minced	1 tsp (2 g) Fresh thyme, chopped	1/2 cup (120 ml) Low-sodium vegetable broth	1 tbsp (15 g) Dijon mustard	1 cup (200 g) No-salt-added canned brown lentils, rinsed and drained	1 cup (225 g) Plain nonfat Greek yogurt, at room temperature	1 cup (140 g) Ready-to-eat cooked farro pouch	1 oz (28 g) Chopped walnuts				Heat the oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat until shimmering.	Add the mushrooms and cook for 5 to 7 minutes, stirring occasionally, until deeply browned and the moisture evaporates.	Stir in the garlic and thyme, and cook for 1 minute until fragrant.	Pour in the broth and mustard, scraping up any browned bits from the bottom of the pan, and bring to a simmer.	Reduce the heat to medium-low, stir in the lentils, and simmer for 2 to 3 minutes. Remove the skillet from the heat.	Warm the farro in the microwave according to the pouch directions. Let the lentil skillet cool off the heat, then stir in the yogurt until smoothly combined so it does not curdle.	Divide the warm farro between serving bowls, top with the mushroom and lentil mixture, and garnish with the walnuts.	Swap the farro for a ready-to-eat brown rice pouch.	Keeps 3 days refrigerated; reheat gently over low heat.	485 kcal	29.8 g	12.7 g	53.3 g	18.9 g	2.2 g	8.5 g	0.0 g*	270 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\creamy_dijon_mushroom_and_lentils_over_farro.png	Cuban-Spiced Pork Medallions with Black Beans and Rice	Pairing lean pork with a base of black beans and brown rice delivers helpful fiber and steady-digesting carbohydrates to keep your energy stable. Slicing the tenderloin into thin medallions ensures it cooks rapidly without drying out.	10 min	11–15 min	10 oz (283 g) Pork tenderloin, cut crosswise into 1/2-inch medallions	1 tsp (2 g) Ground cumin	1 tsp (2 g) Dried oregano	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1/2 medium (55 g) Red onion, chopped	1 medium (119 g) Green bell pepper, chopped	2 cloves (6 g) Garlic, minced	3/4 cup (195 g) No-salt-added canned black beans, rinsed and drained	1 cup (140 g) Ready-to-eat cooked brown rice	2 tbsp (30 ml) Fresh lime juice				Toss the pork medallions with the cumin, oregano, and black pepper in a bowl to coat evenly.	Heat the olive oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat. Add the pork in a single layer and cook for 4 to 6 minutes, flipping halfway, until the meat is browned, then transfer to a plate.	Reduce the heat to medium and add the red onion and green bell pepper to the skillet. Cook for 4 to 5 minutes, stirring occasionally, until the vegetables soften.	Stir the minced garlic into the skillet and cook for 1 minute until fragrant.	Add the rinsed black beans, brown rice, and water to the pan. Cook for 2 to 3 minutes, stirring constantly, until the mixture is steaming and heated through.	Remove the skillet from the heat. Stir in the fresh lime juice, then return the pork medallions and resting juices to the pan, tossing gently to combine.	Divide the rice and vegetable mixture evenly between warm plates, and top with the pork medallions.	Swap the pork tenderloin for boneless, skinless chicken breast pieces.	Keeps 3 days refrigerated; reheat in the microwave until warmed through.	430 kcal	38.7 g	10.1 g	42.9 g	11.5 g	2.3 g	3.8 g	0.0 g*	217 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\cuban-spiced_pork_medallions_with_black_beans_and_rice.png
Five-Spice Turkey Stir-Fry with Bok Choy	This fast, single-skillet dinner relies on quick-cooking turkey breast and a convenient brown rice pouch to keep weeknight preparation simple. Warm Chinese five-spice powder and fresh ginger deliver savory flavor without the heavy sugar of standard sauces.	12 min	6–9 min	8 oz (225 g) Turkey breast cutlets, sliced into thin strips	1 tsp (2 g) Chinese five-spice powder	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1 tbsp (15 g) Fresh ginger, peeled and minced	8 oz (225 g) Sugar snap peas, trimmed	8 oz (225 g) Baby bok choy, chopped	3 tbsp (45 ml) Low-sodium chicken broth	1 tbsp (15 ml) Unseasoned rice vinegar	2 tsp (10 ml) Low-sodium soy sauce	8.8 oz (250 g) Ready-to-eat cooked brown rice pouch	1 tbsp (9 g) Toasted sesame seeds			Toss the turkey strips in a bowl with the Chinese five-spice powder until evenly coated.	Heat the olive oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat. Add the seasoned turkey and cook for 3 to 4 minutes, stirring frequently, until lightly browned.	Add the ginger, sugar snap peas, and bok choy to the skillet. Cook for 2 to 3 minutes, stirring constantly, until the vegetables turn bright green.	Pour the chicken broth, rice vinegar, and low-sodium soy sauce into the pan. Simmer for 1 to 2 minutes, tossing well, until the turkey is cooked through and the sauce lightly coats the ingredients.	Heat the brown rice pouch in the microwave for 1 to 2 minutes until steaming hot.	Divide the warm brown rice between two plates. Top evenly with the turkey and vegetable stir-fry, then garnish with the toasted sesame seeds.		Swap the turkey breast for lean pork tenderloin strips.	Keeps 2 to 3 days refrigerated; reheat on the stovetop.	449 kcal	36.4 g	7.2 g	46.7 g	13.8 g	2.1 g	6.4 g	0.0 g*	355 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\five-spice_turkey_stir-fry_with_bok_choy.png	Garlicky Tempeh, Artichoke, and Spinach Couscous Skillet	This hearty, plant-based dinner provides lasting energy and fullness by pairing protein-dense tempeh with fiber-rich whole-wheat couscous and artichokes.	10 min	7–11 min	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	8 oz (227 g) Tempeh, crumbled	2 cloves (6 g) Garlic, minced	1 tsp (1 g) Dried oregano	1/4 cup (15 g) Sun-dried tomatoes, chopped	1/2 can (120 g) No-salt-added canned artichoke hearts, rinsed, drained, and quartered	2/3 cup (160 ml) Low-sodium vegetable broth	2 cups (60 g) Fresh baby spinach	1/2 cup (85 g) Whole-wheat couscous (dry)	2 tbsp (15 g) Feta cheese, crumbled				Heat olive oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat until shimmering. Add crumbled tempeh and cook for 5 to 7 minutes, stirring occasionally, until golden brown.	Reduce heat to medium. Stir in minced garlic, dried oregano, sun-dried tomatoes, and quartered artichoke hearts, and cook for 1 to 2 minutes until the garlic is fragrant.	Pour in vegetable broth and bring to a simmer. Add baby spinach and stir for 1 to 2 minutes until wilted.	Stir in dry whole-wheat couscous, ensuring it is fully moistened by the broth and mixed with the vegetables.	Remove the skillet from the heat and cover tightly with a lid.	Uncover the skillet after resting and fluff the couscous mixture with a fork. Sprinkle crumbled feta cheese over the top before serving.		Swap the baby spinach for fresh arugula or baby kale.	Keeps 3 days refrigerated; reheat briefly in the microwave.	528 kcal	33.6 g	7.2 g	55.2 g	22.3 g	5.0 g	4.1 g	0.0 g*	194 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\garlicky_tempeh,_artichoke,_and_spinach_couscous_skillet.png
Ginger-Garlic Tofu and Edamame Stir-Fry	Crisp broccoli, tender edamame, and golden tofu soak up a ginger-sesame sauce in this easy skillet meal. Combining two plant proteins provides a satisfying meatless dinner, and a microwave brown rice pouch serves as a quick base.	10 min	9–13 min	12 oz (340 g) Extra-firm tofu, drained, pressed, and cubed	1 cup (150 g) Frozen shelled edamame	2 cups (180 g) Broccoli florets, chopped small	1 pouch (250 g) Microwave brown rice	2 tsp (10 ml) Low-sodium soy sauce	1.5 tbsp (22 ml) Rice vinegar	2 tbsp (30 ml) Water	3 cloves (9 g) Garlic, minced	1 tbsp (6 g) Fresh ginger, minced	1 tsp (5 ml) Toasted sesame oil	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil			Whisk the low-sodium soy sauce, rice vinegar, water, garlic, ginger, and sesame oil in a small bowl.	Heat the extra-virgin olive oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat.	Add the tofu and cook for 5 to 7 minutes, stirring occasionally, until golden brown on most sides.	Stir in the broccoli and frozen edamame, and cook for 3 to 4 minutes until the broccoli turns bright green and the edamame thaws.	Pour the sauce into the skillet and cook for 1 to 2 minutes until the liquid reduces and coats the tofu and vegetables.	Warm the brown rice in the microwave according to the package instructions.	Divide the warm brown rice between plates and top with the tofu and vegetable stir-fry.	Swap the broccoli florets for chopped fresh bok choy.	Keeps 2-3 days refrigerated; reheat in the microwave or a skillet.	511 kcal	32.1 g	9.8 g	48.1 g	24.1 g	3.5 g	5.1 g	0.0 g*	228 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\ginger-garlic_tofu_and_edamame_stir-fry.png	Ginger-Soy Poached Haddock with Bok Choy and Brown Rice	This simple skillet meal provides lean protein and dietary fiber for a satisfying dinner. The savory ginger broth infuses the fish with flavor without adding excess sodium.	10 min	6–8 min	1 tsp (5 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	2 cloves (6 g) Garlic, minced	1 tbsp (6 g) Fresh ginger, minced	1/2 cup (120 ml) No-salt-added vegetable broth	2 tsp (10 ml) Reduced-sodium soy sauce	1 tbsp (15 ml) Unseasoned rice vinegar	9 oz (255 g) Haddock fillets	1 cup (155 g) Frozen shelled edamame	8 oz (227 g) Baby bok choy, quartered	1.5 cups (290 g) Ready-to-eat brown rice pouch	2 medium (30 g) Scallions, thinly sliced			Chop the baby bok choy, mince the garlic and ginger, and slice the scallions.	Heat the olive oil in a large skillet over medium heat, then add the garlic and ginger and cook for 1 minute until fragrant.	Pour in the vegetable broth, reduced-sodium soy sauce, and rice vinegar, and bring the liquid to a simmer.	Nestle the haddock fillets and frozen edamame into the skillet, then cover and simmer for 2 minutes.	Scatter the baby bok choy over the fish and edamame. Cover the skillet and simmer for 3 to 5 minutes, checking at the 3-minute mark to ensure the fish is opaque and flakes easily and the greens are wilted.	Heat the brown rice in the microwave according to the package directions while the fish finishes cooking.	Divide the warm brown rice between serving bowls. Top with the haddock, edamame, and baby bok choy, spoon the broth over the bowls, and garnish with the scallions.	Trade the haddock for cod or peeled large shrimp.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; reheat gently on the stovetop.	413 kcal	36.3 g	7.7 g	49.0 g	8.5 g	0.9 g	4.5 g	0.0 g*	572 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\ginger-soy_poached_haddock_with_bok_choy_and_brown_rice.png
Italian White Bean Stuffed Portobellos with Quinoa	Few ingredients and minimal prep make this plant-based dinner a fast weeknight staple. Meaty portobello caps serve as edible bowls for a savory bean and spinach filling, paired with a convenient quinoa pouch.	10 min	15–18 min	4 caps (340 g) Large portobello mushroom caps, wiped clean and stems removed	2 tsp (10 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	9 oz (250 g) No-salt-added canned cannellini beans, rinsed and drained	2 cups (60 g) Fresh baby spinach, roughly chopped	1/2 cup (125 g) No-added-sugar marinara sauce	1 tsp (3 g) Garlic powder	2.5 oz (70 g) Shredded part-skim mozzarella cheese	1/2 cup (90 g) Ready-to-eat cooked quinoa pouch						Preheat the oven to 400°F / 200°C. Line a baking sheet with parchment paper.	Brush the outsides of the portobello caps with the extra-virgin olive oil and place them gill-side up on the prepared baking sheet.	Mash half of the cannellini beans in a medium bowl using a fork. Stir in the remaining whole beans, spinach, marinara sauce, and garlic powder until combined.	Divide the bean and spinach mixture among the mushroom caps. Sprinkle the shredded mozzarella over the tops.	Bake for 15 to 18 minutes until the mushrooms are tender and the cheese is melted and bubbling.	Warm the quinoa in the microwave according to the pouch instructions while the mushrooms bake.	Serve the stuffed portobellos alongside the warm quinoa.	Swap the baby spinach for finely chopped fresh kale.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; reheat in the oven for 10 minutes.	448 kcal	28.0 g	13.2 g	56.5 g	14.1 g	5.0 g	8.4 g	0.0 g*	518 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\italian_white_bean_stuffed_portobellos_with_quinoa.png	Lemon-Basil Ricotta and Pea Whole-Wheat Pasta	With just one pot and a few simple steps, this stovetop dinner is effortless to prepare. It combines whole-wheat pasta and green peas with a protein-rich blend of part-skim ricotta and Greek yogurt.	10 min	9–11 min	3 oz (85 g) Whole-wheat penne or rotini	1.5 cups (200 g) Frozen green peas	3.5 oz (100 g) Part-skim ricotta cheese	7 oz (200 g) Plain non-fat Greek yogurt	2 cloves (6 g) Garlic, minced	2 tbsp (30 ml) Fresh lemon juice	1 tsp (2 g) Lemon zest	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1/2 tsp (1 g) Black pepper	1/2 cup (12 g) Fresh basil, chopped				Bring a pot of water to a rolling boil over high heat.	Add the pasta and cook for 9 to 11 minutes. Stir in the frozen peas for the final 2 minutes of cooking.	Reserve some of the cooking water, then drain the pasta and peas. Return the mixture to the warm pot off the heat.	Add the ricotta, Greek yogurt, garlic, lemon zest, lemon juice, olive oil, and black pepper directly to the warm pot.	Toss the mixture vigorously, splashing in the reserved cooking water as needed, until a creamy sauce forms and coats the pasta.	Fold in the fresh basil and serve warm.		Swap the frozen green peas for frozen shelled edamame.	Keeps 2-3 days refrigerated; reheat gently on the stovetop.	427 kcal	27.6 g	8.8 g	53.7 g	13.1 g	3.8 g	10.1 g	0.0 g*	197 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\lemon-basil_ricotta_and_pea_whole-wheat_pasta.png
Lemon-Caper Turkey and Asparagus Whole-Wheat Pasta	This fast dinner requires minimal prep and uses a simple skillet technique. Quick-cooking turkey cutlets and whole-wheat angel hair pasta are tossed with asparagus in a bright lemon-caper reduction.	10 min	10–15 min	4 oz (115 g) Whole-wheat angel hair pasta	9 oz (250 g) Fresh asparagus, woody ends trimmed and cut into 2-inch pieces	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	7 oz (200 g) Turkey breast cutlets	2 cloves (6 g) Garlic, minced	1/2 cup (120 ml) Low-sodium chicken broth	2 tbsp (30 ml) Fresh lemon juice	1 tbsp (15 g) Capers, rinsed and drained	2 tbsp (5 g) Fresh flat-leaf parsley, roughly chopped					Bring water to a boil in a medium pot over high heat. Add the pasta and cook for 3 to 5 minutes.	Stir the asparagus into the boiling water during the final 2 minutes of the cooking time. Drain the pasta and asparagus and set aside.	Heat the olive oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat. Cook the turkey cutlets for 2 to 3 minutes per side, flipping at the halfway point. Transfer the turkey to a plate.	Reduce the heat to medium. Add the garlic and cook for 30 to 60 seconds, stirring constantly.	Pour the broth, lemon juice, and capers into the skillet. Simmer for 2 to 3 minutes, scraping the pan to release any browned bits.	Return the turkey, pasta, and asparagus to the skillet. Toss for 1 to 2 minutes to coat the ingredients in the sauce.	Remove the skillet from the heat. Divide the meal between plates and garnish with the parsley.	Swap the turkey breast cutlets for thinly sliced chicken breast.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; reheat gently in a covered skillet.	423 kcal	35.8 g	8.3 g	50.3 g	11.7 g	1.7 g	4.5 g	0.0 g*	276 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\lemon-caper_turkey_and_asparagus_whole-wheat_pasta.png	Lemon-Tahini Tofu and Asparagus Quinoa Bowls	This fast, single-skillet dinner relies on a ready-to-eat quinoa pouch and quick-searing extra-firm tofu to get food on the table with minimal effort. Creamy Greek yogurt stretches the rich tahini dressing to deliver classic Mediterranean flavor.	10 min	10–14 min	1/3 cup (100 g) Nonfat plain Greek yogurt	2 tsp (10 g) Tahini	1 tbsp (15 ml) Fresh lemon juice	1/2 tsp (1 g) Dried oregano, divided	1/2 tsp (2 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	7 oz (200 g) Extra-firm tofu, pressed and cubed	7 oz (200 g) Fresh asparagus, tough ends trimmed, cut into 2-inch pieces	3/4 cup (150 g) Low-sodium canned chickpeas, rinsed and drained	1 cup (150 g) Cherry tomatoes, halved	7 oz (200 g) Plain cooked quinoa, from a ready-to-eat pouch	1/2 tsp (1 g) Garlic powder			Whisk the yogurt, tahini, lemon juice, half of the oregano, and warm water in a small bowl until smooth, then set aside.	Heat the olive oil in a large nonstick skillet over medium-high heat until shimmering, then add the cubed tofu in a single layer.	Cook for 5 to 7 minutes, turning halfway through, until the tofu is golden brown on most sides, then push the tofu to one side of the skillet.	Add the asparagus and water to the empty side of the pan and cook for 3 to 4 minutes, tossing often, until tender-crisp and the water evaporates.	Stir the chickpeas, cherry tomatoes, quinoa, remaining oregano, and garlic powder into the skillet with the tofu and asparagus.	Cook for 2 to 3 minutes, tossing everything together constantly, until the quinoa and tomatoes are fully heated through.	Divide the skillet mixture between plates and drizzle with the creamy dressing to serve.	Swap the asparagus for roughly chopped green beans or zucchini.	Keeps 3 days refrigerated; store the dressing separately and reheat.	414 kcal	28.6 g	12.3 g	50.3 g	13.5 g	1.9 g	10.3 g	0.0 g*	116 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\lemon-tahini_tofu_and_asparagus_quinoa_bowls.png
Mediterranean Chicken, Tomato, and Chickpea Skillet	Simmering bite-sized chicken thighs with crushed tomatoes and chickpeas creates a hearty stew in a single pan. Serve this simple, comforting meal with warm whole-wheat pitas for dipping.	10 min	14–18 min	10.5 oz (300 g) Boneless, skinless chicken thighs, chopped into bite-sized pieces	2 tsp (10 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	7 oz (200 g) Zucchini, sliced into half-moons	1 tsp (3 g) Garlic powder	1 tsp (1 g) Dried oregano	10.5 oz (300 g) No-salt-added canned diced tomatoes, undrained	5.3 oz (150 g) No-salt-added canned chickpeas, rinsed and drained	1 oz (30 g) Kalamata olives, pitted and halved	1 tbsp (15 ml) Fresh lemon juice	2 small (66 g) Small whole-wheat pitas, warmed and halved				Heat the extra-virgin olive oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat until shimmering.	Add the chicken pieces and cook for 4 to 5 minutes until lightly browned on all sides.	Stir in the zucchini, garlic powder, and dried oregano, and cook for 2 to 3 minutes until the zucchini begins to soften.	Pour in the diced tomatoes and chickpeas, stir well to combine, and bring to a rolling simmer.	Reduce the heat to medium-low, cover the skillet, and simmer for 8 to 10 minutes until the chicken is cooked through.	Remove the skillet from the heat, then stir in the kalamata olives and fresh lemon juice.	Serve the warm stew in bowls accompanied by the whole-wheat pitas.	Swap the zucchini for diced eggplant and simmer until tender.	Keeps 3-4 days refrigerated; reheat in a skillet over low heat.	440 kcal	39.3 g	9.8 g	39.7 g	15.1 g	3.0 g	9.5 g	0.0 g*	515 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\mediterranean_chicken,_tomato,_and_chickpea_skillet.png	Mediterranean Halibut and Tomato Skillet	This satisfying skillet meal relies on blistered cherry tomatoes to build a flavorful pan sauce. The savory broth simmers the lean halibut and perfectly seasons the whole-wheat couscous.	10 min	10–14 min	3/4 cup (120 g) Dried whole-wheat couscous	3/4 cup (180 ml) Boiling water	10 oz (280 g) Fresh halibut fillets	1 tsp (2 g) Dried oregano	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	9 oz (250 g) Cherry tomatoes, halved	3 cloves (9 g) Fresh garlic, minced	1/2 cup (120 ml) Low-sodium vegetable broth	4 oz (120 g) Baby spinach	1/4 cup (30 g) Low-sodium Kalamata olives, pitted, rinsed, drained and halved	2 tbsp (30 ml) Fresh lemon juice			Place the couscous in a heatproof bowl. Pour in the boiling water, cover tightly, let sit for 5 minutes to hydrate, and fluff with a fork.	Season the halibut with the dried oregano, black pepper, and salt.	Heat the olive oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat. Sear the halibut for 3 to 4 minutes on one side until golden, flip the fish, and transfer to a plate.	Reduce the heat to medium and add the cherry tomatoes and garlic to the skillet. Cook for 4 to 5 minutes, stirring occasionally, until the tomatoes begin to blister and burst.	Pour in the vegetable broth, scraping up any browned bits from the pan. Stir in the spinach and olives, cooking for 1 to 2 minutes until the spinach wilts.	Return the halibut to the skillet. Simmer for 2 to 3 minutes, spooning the tomato sauce over the fish, until the fish is completely opaque and flakes easily.	Remove the skillet from the heat and pour in the lemon juice. Serve the halibut and blistered tomato sauce over the steamed couscous.	Swap the halibut for an equal amount of peeled shrimp.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; reheat gently on the stovetop.	488 kcal	37.1 g	6.2 g	57.5 g	12.1 g	1.9 g	4.1 g	0.0 g*	266 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\mediterranean_halibut_and_tomato_skillet.png
Mediterranean Lentil and Feta Stuffed Sweet Potatoes	This meatless meal delivers a lasting hit of protein and fiber to keep your energy steady. Microwaving the sweet potatoes creates a fast weeknight base, cleverly stacked with lentils, Greek yogurt, and walnuts to satisfy without heavy prep.	10 min	8–11 min	2 (250 g) Small sweet potatoes, scrubbed	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	2 cloves (6 g) Garlic, minced	1 tsp (2 g) Ground cumin	7 oz (200 g) No-salt-added canned lentils, rinsed and drained	2 cups (60 g) Baby spinach	7 oz (200 g) Plain nonfat Greek yogurt	1 tbsp (15 ml) Lemon juice	1.5 oz (42 g) Feta cheese, crumbled	1 oz (28 g) Walnuts, chopped				Prick the sweet potatoes all over with a fork. Place on a microwave-safe plate and microwave on High for 6 to 8 minutes, turning halfway, until the centers are completely tender.	While the potatoes microwave, heat the olive oil in a skillet over medium heat until shimmering. Add the garlic and cumin; stir for about 30 seconds until fragrant.	Add the lentils and spinach to the skillet. Cook for 2 to 3 minutes, tossing frequently, until the spinach is fully wilted and the lentils are heated through. Remove from the heat.	Whisk the Greek yogurt and lemon juice together in a small bowl until smooth.	Split the hot sweet potatoes open down the center. Divide the lentil and spinach mixture evenly, stuffing it inside and over the top of the potatoes.	Drizzle the yogurt sauce over each portion, then sprinkle evenly with the feta cheese and walnuts.		Trade the chopped walnuts for toasted pumpkin or sunflower seeds.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; reheat potato and lentils before topping.	513 kcal	27.5 g	13.4 g	54.7 g	22.3 g	4.9 g	11.0 g	0.0 g*	372 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\mediterranean_lentil_and_feta_stuffed_sweet_potatoes.png	Moroccan Chicken and Chickpea Skillet with Quinoa	Cinnamon is typically reserved for baking, but in North African cooking, it brings a warm, savory depth that transforms a simple pan sauce. Built with pre-cooked quinoa and tender chicken, this braise delivers complex flavors without demanding hours on the stove.	10 min	10–14 min	8 oz (220 g) Chicken tenderloins, cut into bite-sized pieces	1 tsp (2 g) Ground cumin	1 tsp (2 g) Smoked paprika	1/4 tsp (0.5 g) Ground cinnamon	1/4 tsp (1.5 g) Kosher salt	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	2 cloves (6 g) Garlic, minced	1 cup (240 g) No-salt-added diced tomatoes, with juice	1/2 cup (130 g) No-salt-added canned chickpeas, rinsed and drained	1 cup (185 g) Ready-to-eat cooked quinoa pouch	3 cups (90 g) Fresh baby spinach	1 tbsp (15 ml) Fresh lemon juice		Toss the chicken in a medium bowl with the ground cumin, smoked paprika, ground cinnamon, and salt until evenly coated.	Heat the extra-virgin olive oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat. Add the chicken and cook until lightly browned on the bottom, 3 to 4 minutes.	Flip the chicken and add the minced garlic to the skillet. Stir and cook for 1 to 2 minutes.	Pour the diced tomatoes with their juices, rinsed chickpeas, and cooked quinoa into the skillet. Stir to combine and bring to a simmer.	Reduce the heat to medium-low, cover, and cook until the chicken is completely opaque and the quinoa is warmed, 5 to 6 minutes.	Remove the lid and stir in the baby spinach. Cook until the spinach wilts, 1 to 2 minutes.	Remove the skillet from the heat, stir in the fresh lemon juice, and divide between two plates.	Swap the chicken for turkey breast or boneless pork loin.	Keeps 3 days refrigerated; reheat gently on the stovetop.	405 kcal	34.8 g	9.4 g	37.0 g	13.8 g	2.0 g	6.1 g	0.0 g*	483 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\moroccan_chicken_and_chickpea_skillet_with_quinoa.png
One-Skillet Lemon-Herb Turkey and Quinoa	Bright lemon and savory browned turkey flavor this simple Mediterranean skillet. Simmering the quinoa directly in the broth builds rich flavor and adds fiber using just one pan.	7 min	17–23 min	2 tsp (10 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	10 oz (283 g) Lean ground turkey (93% lean)	2 cloves (6 g) Fresh garlic, minced	1 tsp (1 g) Dried oregano	2/3 cup (113 g) Quinoa, rinsed and drained	1 1/3 cups (315 ml) Low-sodium chicken broth	1 medium (200 g) Zucchini, diced	1 cup (150 g) Cherry tomatoes, halved	1/4 tsp (1.5 g) Salt	1 medium (50 g) Fresh lemon, zested and juiced	2 cups (60 g) Baby spinach			Heat the oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat until shimmering.	Add the turkey, breaking it apart with a spatula, and cook until browned, 4 to 6 minutes.	Stir in the garlic and oregano and cook until fragrant, 1 to 2 minutes.	Stir in the quinoa, broth, zucchini, tomatoes, and salt, then bring to a rolling boil.	Reduce the heat to low, cover, and simmer until the liquid is absorbed and the quinoa is tender, 12 to 15 minutes.	Remove the skillet from the heat, then fold in the spinach, lemon zest, and lemon juice.	Cover the skillet and let stand off the heat until the spinach wilts before serving.	Swap the zucchini for diced red or green bell pepper.	Keeps 3 days refrigerated; reheat gently in the microwave.	540 kcal	40.9 g	7.5 g	48.9 g	21.9 g	4.6 g	5.5 g	0.0 g*	475 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\one-skillet_lemon-herb_turkey_and_quinoa.png	Pan-Seared Trout with Lemon-Dill Quinoa and Peas	Instead of boiling a separate pot for grains, this technique tosses a ready-to-eat quinoa pouch directly into the skillet to absorb the savory pan juices left by the trout. It perfectly bridges the gap between whole-food nutrition and a weeknight pantry shortcut.	10 min	7–11 min	9 oz (255 g) Rainbow trout fillets, patted dry	1/2 tsp (1 g) Black pepper	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	8.5 oz (240 g) Ready-to-eat cooked quinoa pouch	1 1/2 cups (200 g) Frozen green peas	3 oz (85 g) Fresh baby spinach	2 tbsp (30 ml) Lemon juice, freshly squeezed	1 tbsp (15 g) Dijon mustard	1/4 cup (4 g) Fresh dill, chopped					Pat the trout dry with a paper towel and season the flesh evenly with the black pepper.	Heat the extra-virgin olive oil in a large nonstick skillet over medium-high heat until shimmering. Place the trout skin-side down and cook for 3 to 4 minutes, until the skin is crisp. Check at 3 minutes.	Carefully flip the trout and cook for 1 to 2 minutes, until the flesh is opaque and flakes easily. Transfer the trout to a plate and cover loosely to keep warm.	Reduce the skillet heat to medium. Add the ready-to-eat quinoa and frozen peas to the remaining pan juices. Cook for 2 to 3 minutes, stirring frequently until heated through. Check at 2 minutes.	Add the baby spinach to the skillet and toss for 1 to 2 minutes, until just wilted. Remove the skillet from the heat.	Stir the lemon juice, Dijon mustard, and fresh dill directly into the warm quinoa mixture, mixing well to combine the flavors.	Divide the warm quinoa and pea salad between two plates and top each with a pan-seared trout fillet.	Swap the trout fillets for boneless, skinless salmon or tilapia.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; reheat gently in the microwave.	482 kcal	37.6 g	9.3 g	42.7 g	18.1 g	3.1 g	6.7 g	0.0 g*	299 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\pan-seared_trout_with_lemon-dill_quinoa_and_peas.png
Parchment-Baked Lemon Cod with Zucchini and Couscous	Cooking in folded parchment paper locks in moisture and infuses the fish with bright Mediterranean flavors. Whole wheat couscous steams easily on the counter to complete this simple meal.	10 min	12–15 min	12 oz (340 g) Skinless cod fillets, patted dry	12 oz (340 g) Zucchini, diced	8 oz (225 g) Cherry tomatoes, halved	1 oz (30 g) Kalamata olives, low-sodium, rinsed, drained, and halved	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1 tsp (2 g) Dried oregano	1/2 tsp (1 g) Black pepper	1/4 tsp (1.5 g) Salt	1 medium Fresh lemon, halved	1/2 cup (85 g) Whole wheat couscous, dry	1/2 cup (120 ml) Boiling water			Preheat the oven to 400°F / 200°C. Tear off large squares of parchment paper.	Toss the zucchini, cherry tomatoes, olives, extra-virgin olive oil, oregano, black pepper, and salt in a bowl.	Divide the vegetable mixture onto the parchment sheets and top with the cod fillets. Squeeze lemon juice over the fish, then fold the parchment edges tightly to seal into packets.	Place the packets on a baking sheet and bake for 12 to 15 minutes. Check the fish at 12 minutes to ensure it is opaque and flakes easily.	Place the whole wheat couscous in a heatproof bowl. Pour the boiling water over the grains, cover tightly, and let sit for 5 minutes.	Fluff the couscous with a fork. Cut the remaining lemon into wedges.	Divide the couscous onto plates. Open the hot packets carefully, slide the cod and vegetables over the grains, and serve with the lemon wedges.	Swap the cod fillets for equal amounts of peeled shrimp.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; reheat gently in the oven.	460 kcal	39.4 g	7.0 g	46.9 g	13.1 g	2.0 g	8.0 g	0.0 g*	484 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\parchment-baked_lemon_cod_with_zucchini_and_couscous.png	Parchment-Baked Snapper with Artichokes and Farro	This parchment packet technique creates a fully composed dinner with zero pans to wash. Red snapper steams alongside a bed of Mediterranean vegetables and hearty farro.	10 min	12–15 min	10.6 oz (300 g) Fresh or frozen red snapper fillets, thawed	7 oz (200 g) Ready-to-eat cooked farro pouch, unsalted	5.3 oz (150 g) No-salt-added canned artichoke hearts, rinsed, drained, and quartered	5.3 oz (150 g) Cherry tomatoes, halved	1 oz (30 g) Kalamata olives, pitted, halved	2 cloves (6 g) Fresh garlic, minced	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1 tsp (2 g) Dried oregano	1 medium (60 g) Fresh lemon, cut in half					Preheat the oven to 400°F / 200°C. Cut two large rectangles of parchment paper and lay them flat on a baking sheet.	Toss the farro, artichoke hearts, cherry tomatoes, olives, minced garlic, olive oil, and dried oregano together in a mixing bowl.	Divide the farro and vegetable mixture evenly and mound it onto the center of each parchment sheet.	Place the snapper fillets directly on top of each mound.	Squeeze half of the lemon over the fillets, then slice the remaining lemon and arrange the slices over the fish.	Fold the long sides of each parchment paper up and crimp the edges tightly to seal them into airtight packets.	Bake for 12 to 15 minutes until the fish is opaque and flakes easily with a fork. Open the hot packets carefully and serve.	Swap the red snapper for peeled and deveined medium shrimp.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated in an airtight container; reheat gently.	438 kcal	39.3 g	10.7 g	45.3 g	12.2 g	1.8 g	3.5 g	0.0 g*	256 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\parchment-baked_snapper_with_artichokes_and_farro.png
Sesame-Seared Tuna with Snap Peas and Brown Rice	A steady supply of lean protein and dietary fiber helps maintain lasting energy throughout the busy week. This quick skillet dinner delivers a steakhouse-style seafood experience using accessible freezer staples.	10 min	5–8 min	1 pouch (8.5 oz / 240 g) Ready-to-eat cooked brown rice pouch	8 oz (225 g) Fresh or frozen tuna steaks (thawed)	1 tbsp (9 g) Sesame seeds	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	2 medium (30 g) Scallions, sliced	8 oz (225 g) Fresh sugar snap peas, trimmed	1/2 cup (80 g) Frozen shelled edamame, thawed	1 tbsp (15 g) Fresh ginger paste	2 tsp (10 ml) Low-sodium soy sauce	1 tbsp (15 ml) Unseasoned rice vinegar				Microwave the brown rice pouch according to the package directions and set aside.	Pat the tuna steaks dry with a paper towel and press them firmly into the sesame seeds to coat both sides evenly.	Heat the extra-virgin olive oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat until shimmering. Sear the tuna for 1 to 2 minutes per side, flipping halfway through, until the crust is toasted and the center remains pink, then transfer to a cutting board.	Reduce the burner heat to medium, then add the scallions, sugar snap peas, edamame, and ginger paste to the skillet.	Stir-fry for 3 to 4 minutes until the peas are bright green and crisp-tender, then remove from the heat and stir in the low-sodium soy sauce and rice vinegar.	Slice the seared tuna. Divide the warm brown rice between plates, top with the vegetable mixture, and arrange the tuna slices over the top.		Swap the sugar snap peas for fresh or frozen broccoli florets.	Best enjoyed right away; seared tuna does not reheat well.	473 kcal	40.3 g	8.1 g	46.9 g	13.8 g	2.1 g	6.2 g	0.0 g*	246 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\sesame-seared_tuna_with_snap_peas_and_brown_rice.png	Sheet-Pan Lemon-Dill Salmon with Potatoes and Green Beans	This single-pan meal brings together salmon, skin-on potatoes, and crisp greens for a filling combination of lean protein and dietary fiber. A mustard and herb coating keeps the fish flavorful without relying on heavy sauces.	8 min	20–22 min	10 oz (285 g) Salmon, fillets, untreated	14 oz (400 g) Baby potatoes, cut into 1/2-inch cubes	8 oz (225 g) Fresh green beans, trimmed	2 tsp (10 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1 tsp (3 g) Garlic powder	1/4 tsp (1.5 g) Salt	1/2 tsp (1 g) Black pepper	1 tbsp (15 g) Whole grain mustard	2 tbsp (30 ml) Lemon juice, freshly squeezed	1 tbsp (3 g) Fresh dill, chopped	1 tbsp (8 g) Sliced almonds			Preheat the oven to 425°F / 220°C for 5 minutes.	Toss the cubed potatoes directly on a baking sheet with the olive oil, garlic powder, salt, and black pepper.	Spread the potatoes into an even layer and roast for 10 minutes until they begin to soften.	Mix the whole grain mustard, lemon juice, and fresh dill in a small bowl.	Remove the baking sheet from the oven, push the potatoes to one side, and place the green beans in the middle.	Place the salmon fillets on the remaining open third of the pan and spoon the mustard mixture evenly over the fish.	Return the pan to the oven and roast for 10 to 12 minutes, checking at 10 minutes, until the salmon is opaque and flakes easily with a fork. Scatter the almonds over the top before serving.	Swap the fresh green beans for trimmed asparagus spears.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; reheat gently in the oven.	470 kcal	36.0 g	8.3 g	46.6 g	16.4 g	2.3 g	6.0 g	0.0 g*	457 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\sheet-pan_lemon-dill_salmon_with_potatoes_and_green_beans.png
Skillet Chicken and Green Pea Curry Bowls	Perfect for a busy weeknight dinner, this spiced skillet dish swaps traditional heavy cream for plain Greek yogurt to build a rich, comforting sauce.	10 min	10–15 min	8 oz (227 g) Boneless, skinless chicken breast tenders, cut into bite-sized chunks	2 tsp (10 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	2 cloves (6 g) Garlic, minced	1 tbsp (6 g) Yellow curry powder	1 cup (240 g) No-salt-added canned crushed tomatoes	1 cup (134 g) Frozen green peas	1 1/2 cups (240 g) Ready-to-eat cooked brown rice pouch	1/3 cup (75 g) Nonfat plain Greek yogurt	1/4 cup (4 g) Fresh cilantro, chopped					Warm the extra-virgin olive oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat until shimmering.	Add the chicken chunks and cook for 4 to 6 minutes, stirring occasionally, until browned on the outside. Check at 4 minutes.	Lower the heat to medium. Stir in the minced garlic and yellow curry powder, cooking for 1 to 2 minutes until fragrant. Check at 1 minute.	Pour in the crushed tomatoes and frozen green peas, stirring to combine. Bring to a gentle simmer and cook for 5 to 7 minutes until the chicken is completely cooked through and the sauce thickens. Check at 5 minutes.	Warm the brown rice pouch in the microwave according to the package directions while the curry simmers.	Remove the skillet from the heat. Stir the Greek yogurt into the curry until smoothly incorporated into a creamy sauce.	Divide the warm brown rice between two shallow bowls. Spoon the chicken curry over the top and garnish with fresh chopped cilantro.	Swap the frozen green peas for small frozen broccoli florets.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; reheat gently to maintain sauce texture.	422 kcal	37.3 g	9.2 g	45.6 g	10.1 g	1.7 g	7.8 g	0.0 g*	153 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\skillet_chicken_and_green_pea_curry_bowls.png	Skillet Pork Chops with Apple, Squash, and Farro	Providing fiber and lean protein, this one-pan dinner helps keep your energy steady. Crisp apple naturally balances the savory mustard sauce without requiring added sugar.	10 min	11–15 min	10 oz (283 g) Boneless pork loin chops, patted dry	1/8 tsp (1 g) Salt	1/2 tsp (2 g) Garlic powder	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1.5 cups (210 g) Frozen butternut squash chunks	1 medium (150 g) Crisp apple (such as Fuji or Gala), cored and diced	1 tbsp (2 g) Fresh sage, chopped	1/4 cup (60 ml) Low-sodium chicken broth	2 tbsp (30 ml) Apple cider vinegar	1 tbsp (15 g) Dijon mustard	5.5 oz (156 g) Unseasoned ready-to-eat cooked farro, from a pouch	2 cups (60 g) Fresh baby spinach		Season the pork chops on both sides with salt and garlic powder.	Heat the extra-virgin olive oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat. Add the pork chops and sear for 4 to 5 minutes per side, flipping halfway, until golden brown. Transfer the pork to a plate and cover to keep warm.	Add the butternut squash and diced apple to the same skillet. Cook over medium heat for 4 to 5 minutes, stirring, until the squash softens and lightly browns.	Stir in the fresh sage, low-sodium chicken broth, apple cider vinegar, and Dijon mustard, scraping up any browned bits from the bottom of the pan. Simmer the liquid for 1 to 2 minutes until it thickens.	Stir in the cooked farro and baby spinach. Toss for 1 to 2 minutes until the spinach wilts and the grains are hot.	Return the warm pork chops and any resting juices to the skillet. Heat for 1 minute before dividing everything between two plates.		Swap the butternut squash for frozen cubed sweet potatoes.	Keeps 2-3 days refrigerated; reheat gently in a covered skillet.	510 kcal	38.3 g	7.4 g	50.4 g	17.7 g	4.3 g	13.0 g	0.0 g*	391 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\skillet_pork_chops_with_apple,_squash,_and_farro.png
Skillet Turkey Puttanesca with Zucchini and Quinoa	This simple, one-pan Mediterranean meal comes together rapidly thanks to a few briny pantry staples. Quick-cooking turkey cutlets and a ready-to-eat quinoa pouch keep the active cooking fast and the total time well under thirty minutes.	10 min	13–18 min	9 oz (255 g) Turkey breast cutlets	1/2 tsp (1 g) Black pepper	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	10 oz (300 g) Zucchini, diced	2 cloves (6 g) Garlic, minced	14.5 oz (411 g) No-salt-added diced tomatoes, undrained	1 oz (28 g) Kalamata olives, pitted and halved	1 tbsp (9 g) Capers, rinsed and drained	1 tbsp (15 ml) Red wine vinegar	8.5 oz (240 g) Ready-to-eat cooked quinoa pouch	1/4 cup (6 g) Fresh basil, chopped			Season turkey cutlets on both sides with black pepper. Heat olive oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat until shimmering.	Add turkey to the skillet and cook for 4 to 6 minutes total, flipping halfway, until browned. Check at 4 minutes, then transfer turkey to a plate.	Lower heat to medium. Add zucchini to the skillet and cook for 3 to 4 minutes until slightly softened. Stir in garlic and cook for 1 minute until fragrant.	Pour diced tomatoes with their juices, olives, capers, and red wine vinegar into the skillet. Bring mixture to a rolling simmer.	Return turkey cutlets to the skillet, nestling them into the sauce. Reduce heat to low, cover, and simmer for 5 to 7 minutes until turkey is cooked through and sauce thickens slightly. Check at 5 minutes.	Tear a small vent in the top of the quinoa pouch and microwave on high for 90 seconds until steaming hot.	Divide hot quinoa between two plates. Top with turkey, spoon zucchini puttanesca sauce over meat, and sprinkle with fresh basil.	Swap the turkey breast for quick-cooking chicken breast tenders.	Keeps 2-3 days refrigerated; reheat gently on the stovetop or microwave.	439 kcal	39.0 g	9.4 g	39.8 g	15.4 g	2.3 g	10.1 g	0.0 g*	345 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\skillet_turkey_puttanesca_with_zucchini_and_quinoa.png	Skillet White Bean and Zucchini Pizza Bake	This savory one-pan meal delivers plenty of vegetables and plant-based protein for lasting fullness. Creamy navy beans replace a refined flour crust, providing a comforting, high-fiber base for classic pizza flavors.	10 min	12–16 min	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	7 oz (200 g) Zucchini, chopped	8 oz (225 g) Cremini mushrooms, sliced	1 tsp (3 g) Garlic powder	1 tsp (1 g) Dried oregano	8.8 oz (250 g) No-salt-added navy beans, rinsed and drained	1 cup (240 g) No-salt-added canned crushed tomatoes	1/2 cup (56 g) Part-skim mozzarella cheese, shredded	2 tbsp (10 g) Parmesan cheese, grated					Preheat the oven to 400°F / 200°C.	Heat the olive oil in an oven-safe skillet over medium-high heat until shimmering.	Sauté the zucchini and mushrooms in the skillet until softened and lightly browned, 5 to 7 minutes.	Stir the garlic powder, dried oregano, navy beans, and crushed tomatoes into the skillet.	Reduce the heat to medium and simmer until the sauce thickens slightly, 3 to 4 minutes.	Remove the skillet from the heat and sprinkle the shredded mozzarella and grated Parmesan evenly over the top.	Transfer the skillet to the oven and bake until the cheese is melted and bubbling, 4 to 5 minutes.	Swap the cremini mushrooms for diced green bell peppers.	Keeps 3 days refrigerated; reheat in the microwave.	408 kcal	23.6 g	17.4 g	48.4 g	15.5 g	5.2 g	8.5 g	0.0 g*	305 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\skillet_white_bean_and_zucchini_pizza_bake.png
Smoky Chicken and Sweet Potato Skillet Hash	A covered-skillet steaming trick makes this meal fast to prepare. Tender sweet potatoes, smoky chicken thighs, and hearty kale anchor a satisfying, high-fiber hash.	10 min	14–20 min	12 oz (340 g) Boneless, skinless chicken thighs, diced into bite-sized pieces	1 tsp (2 g) Smoked paprika	1/2 tsp (1 g) Garlic powder	1/4 tsp (1.5 g) Salt	1/4 tsp (0.5 g) Black pepper	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	12 oz (340 g) Sweet potatoes, peeled and diced small	2.5 oz (70 g) Red onion, diced	1/4 cup (60 ml) Low-sodium chicken broth	3.5 oz (100 g) Bagged chopped kale, tough stems removed	1 tbsp (15 ml) Apple cider vinegar	2 tbsp (18 g) Raw pumpkin seeds (pepitas)		Toss the chicken with the smoked paprika, garlic powder, salt, and black pepper in a medium bowl.	Heat the oil in a large skillet with a tight-fitting lid over medium-high heat. Add the seasoned chicken and cook for 3 to 4 minutes until browned on the outside, then transfer it to a plate.	Add the sweet potatoes and red onion to the same skillet. Cook for 2 to 3 minutes, stirring to pick up any browned bits from the bottom of the pan.	Pour in the chicken broth and immediately cover the skillet. Reduce the heat to medium-low and steam for 6 to 8 minutes, checking at 6 minutes, until the sweet potatoes are tender.	Uncover the skillet and stir in the kale. Cook for 1 to 2 minutes until the leaves begin to wilt.	Return the chicken and any resting juices to the skillet. Drizzle with the apple cider vinegar and cook for 2 to 3 minutes until the chicken is completely cooked through and the moisture has mostly evaporated.	Divide the hash between plates and top with the pumpkin seeds before serving.	Swap the chopped kale for fresh spinach or Swiss chard.	Keeps 2 to 3 days refrigerated; reheat in a warm skillet.	507 kcal	41.5 g	8.7 g	42.1 g	19.6 g	3.8 g	9.4 g	0.0 g*	585 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\smoky_chicken_and_sweet_potato_skillet_hash.png	Smoky Scallop, Corn, and Zucchini Quinoa Skillet	Delivering lean protein and steady energy, this quick stovetop meal helps keep you full on busy weeknights. Scallops cook in minutes alongside high-fiber vegetables for a vibrant, all-in-one skillet.	10 min	8–11 min	12 oz (340 g) Sea scallops, untreated / no salt added, side muscle removed	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil, divided	1 medium (200 g) Zucchini, diced	1 medium (150 g) Red bell pepper, diced	1 cup (145 g) Frozen sweet corn	8.8 oz (250 g) Ready-to-eat cooked quinoa pouch	1 tsp (2 g) Smoked paprika, divided	1 tsp (3 g) Garlic powder, divided	2 tbsp (30 ml) Fresh lime juice	1/4 cup (8 g) Fresh cilantro, chopped				Pat the scallops dry with a paper towel. Season them with half the smoked paprika, half the garlic powder, and the black pepper.	Heat half the olive oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat. Add the scallops and sear for 4 to 6 minutes, flipping halfway through, until golden brown on the outside and mostly opaque in the center. Transfer the scallops to a plate and set aside.	Add the remaining olive oil, diced zucchini, diced red bell pepper, and frozen sweet corn to the same skillet. Sauté over medium-high heat for 4 to 5 minutes, stirring occasionally, until the vegetables begin to soften and char.	Crumble the quinoa into the skillet with the vegetables. Stir in the remaining smoked paprika, remaining garlic powder, and the water to lift any browned bits from the pan. Cook for 2 to 3 minutes until heated through.	Return the scallops and any resting juices to the skillet. Drizzle the lime juice over the top and sprinkle with the chopped cilantro.	Toss the mixture to combine, remove the skillet from the heat, and serve immediately.		Swap the sea scallops for untreated large peeled shrimp.	Best enjoyed right away; leftover scallops do not reheat well.	474 kcal	38.6 g	8.3 g	57.8 g	12.0 g	1.7 g	9.0 g	0.0 g*	300 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\smoky_scallop,_corn,_and_zucchini_quinoa_skillet.png
Spanish-Style Butter Bean and Quinoa Egg Skillet	A steady delivery of fiber and lean protein helps maintain lasting fullness, making this robust one-pan dinner a smart weeknight choice.	10 min	9–12 min	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	3 cloves Garlic, minced	1 tsp (2 g) Smoked paprika	1 cup (240 g) No-salt-added crushed tomatoes	9 oz (260 g) No-salt-added canned butter beans, rinsed and drained	1 tbsp (15 ml) Red wine vinegar	1 cup (150 g) Ready-to-eat cooked quinoa pouch	2 loosely packed cups (60 g) Fresh baby spinach	4 Large eggs	1/2 cup (115 g) Plain nonfat Greek yogurt	2 tbsp (8 g) Fresh parsley, chopped			Heat olive oil in a large skillet over medium heat until shimmering. Add minced garlic and smoked paprika, stirring constantly for 30 seconds until fragrant.	Pour in crushed tomatoes, butter beans, and red wine vinegar. Bring the mixture to a gentle simmer.	Fold quinoa and baby spinach into the simmering sauce. Stir continuously for 2 to 3 minutes until the spinach wilts.	Form small, deep wells in the bean and quinoa mixture using the back of a spoon. Crack eggs into the wells.	Cover the skillet tightly with a lid and reduce the heat to medium-low. Cook for 5 to 7 minutes, checking at 5 minutes, until the egg whites are firmly set but the yolks remain soft.	Remove the skillet from the heat. Dollop Greek yogurt around the edges and scatter chopped parsley over the top before serving in shallow bowls.		Swap the butter beans for low-sodium canned chickpeas.	Best enjoyed right away; soft-cooked eggs do not reheat well.	469 kcal	30.5 g	11.7 g	45.3 g	19.1 g	4.4 g	7.4 g	0.0 g*	237 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\spanish-style_butter_bean_and_quinoa_egg_skillet.png	Spiced Red Lentil and Spinach Stew	This simple one-pot stew relies on quick-cooking dry red lentils and pre-chopped onion for a fast weeknight dinner. Nonfat Greek yogurt adds creamy richness and protein while skipping the saturated fat of coconut milk.	5 min	18–23 min	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	3.5 oz (100 g) Pre-chopped yellow onion	2 cloves Minced garlic, minced	1 tbsp (6 g) Curry powder	4.2 oz (120 g) Dry red lentils, rinsed	8.5 oz (240 g) No-salt-added canned diced tomatoes, with juices	2 cups (480 ml) Low-sodium vegetable broth	3.5 oz (100 g) Fresh baby spinach	10.6 oz (300 g) Nonfat plain Greek yogurt	0.4 oz (10 g) Fresh cilantro, chopped				Heat the extra-virgin olive oil in a medium pot over medium heat until shimmering. Add the yellow onion and minced garlic, and cook until softened, about 3 to 4 minutes.	Stir in the curry powder and cook for 30 seconds.	Pour in the dry red lentils, diced tomatoes with their juices, and vegetable broth. Increase the heat to medium-high and bring to a gentle boil.	Reduce the heat to low, cover the pot tightly, and simmer until the lentils are tender and the liquid is absorbed. Check at 12 minutes, cooking for 12 to 15 minutes total.	Remove the pot from the heat. Fold in the baby spinach, stirring until the residual heat wilts the leaves, then let the stew sit for 2 minutes to cool.	Fold in the Greek yogurt and chopped cilantro until the stew becomes creamy and uniform in color. Plate and serve immediately.		Swap the baby spinach for chopped kale or Swiss chard.	Keeps 3 days refrigerated; reheat gently over low heat without boiling.	453 kcal	33.8 g	12.3 g	60.6 g	10.2 g	1.4 g	12.2 g	0.0 g*	467 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Dinner\IMG\spiced_red_lentil_and_spinach_stew.png
