Title_1	Introduction_1	Preparation_time_1	Cooking_1	Ingredient_1_1	Ingredient_2_1	Ingredient_3_1	Ingredient_4_1	Ingredient_5_1	Ingredient_6_1	Ingredient_7_1	Ingredient_8_1	Ingredient_9_1	Ingredient_10_1	Ingredient_11_1	Ingredient_12_1	Ingredient_13_1	Instruction_1_1	Instruction_2_1	Instruction_3_1	Instruction_4_1	Instruction_5_1	Instruction_6_1	Instruction_7_1	Variation_1	Storage_1	Calories_1	Protein_1	Fiber_1	Carbs_1	TotalFat_1	SaturatedFat_1	TotalSugars_1	AddedSugars_1	Sodium_1	@Image_1	Title_2	Introduction_2	Preparation_time_2	Cooking_2	Ingredient_1_2	Ingredient_2_2	Ingredient_3_2	Ingredient_4_2	Ingredient_5_2	Ingredient_6_2	Ingredient_7_2	Ingredient_8_2	Ingredient_9_2	Ingredient_10_2	Ingredient_11_2	Ingredient_12_2	Ingredient_13_2	Instruction_1_2	Instruction_2_2	Instruction_3_2	Instruction_4_2	Instruction_5_2	Instruction_6_2	Instruction_7_2	Variation_2	Storage_2	Calories_2	Protein_2	Fiber_2	Carbs_2	TotalFat_2	SaturatedFat_2	TotalSugars_2	AddedSugars_2	Sodium_2	@Image_2
Balsamic Steak and Artichoke Farro Bowls	Most bistros serve steak with heavy fries, but pairing it with hearty farro and fiber-rich artichokes creates a more balanced meal.	10 min	4–6 min	10 oz (285 g) Lean sirloin steak strips, cut into 1-inch strips	8.5 oz (240 g) Ready-to-eat cooked farro pouch	1 can, drained (240 g) Canned artichoke hearts (in water, no-salt-added), halved	1 cup (150 g) Cherry tomatoes, halved	2 cups (60 g) Baby arugula	2 tbsp (30 ml) Balsamic vinegar	1 tbsp plus 1 tsp (20 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil, divided	1 tsp (5 g) Dijon mustard	1/2 tsp (1 g) Garlic powder	1/4 tsp (0.5 g) Black pepper				Whisk the balsamic vinegar, olive oil, Dijon mustard, garlic powder, and black pepper in a large mixing bowl to create a dressing.	Add the artichoke hearts, cherry tomatoes, and arugula to the bowl. Toss to coat, then divide the salad mixture into serving bowls.	Heat the farro according to the pouch instructions. Spoon the warm grain over the salad bases.	Pat the steak strips dry with a paper towel. Heat the olive oil in a skillet over medium-high heat.	Add the steak in a single layer. Sear for 4 to 6 minutes, flipping halfway through, until browned.	Remove the skillet from the heat and let the meat rest in the pan to retain its juices.	Top each bowl with the rested steak strips and serve immediately.	Swap the sirloin steak strips for boneless, skinless chicken breast.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; pack the steak and farro separately.	535 kcal	42.3 g	12.2 g	54.5 g	17.8 g	3.7 g	3.9 g	0.0 g*	222 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\balsamic_steak_and_artichoke_farro_bowls.png	Blistered Tomato and Artichoke Cottage Cheese Bowls	A satisfying working lunch needs to be quick to assemble but substantial enough to carry you through the afternoon. This bowl plays the warm, tangy pop of blistered vegetables against a cool, creamy bed of savory cottage cheese.	10 min	4–6 min	1 1/2 cups (350 g) Low-sodium low-fat cottage cheese (2% milkfat)	1 cup (200 g) Cherry tomatoes, halved	7 oz (200 g) Canned no-salt-added artichoke hearts, rinsed, drained, and roughly chopped	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1/2 tsp (1 g) Garlic powder	1 tbsp (15 ml) Balsamic vinegar	1/2 tsp (1 g) Black pepper	3 tbsp (30 g) Shelled unsalted pistachios, roughly chopped	1/4 cup (10 g) Fresh basil, torn	2 medium (100 g) Whole-wheat pitas, warmed and cut into wedges				Toss the tomatoes, chopped artichokes, and garlic powder together in a medium bowl.	Heat the olive oil in a skillet over medium-high heat until shimmering.	Add the tomato and artichoke mixture to the skillet and cook for 4 to 6 minutes, stirring occasionally, until the tomatoes begin to burst and the artichokes brown.	Remove the skillet from the heat and stir in the balsamic vinegar and black pepper, scraping up any browned bits from the bottom of the pan.	Divide the cold cottage cheese evenly between shallow bowls.	Spoon the warm tomato and artichoke mixture directly over the cottage cheese.	Top with the chopped pistachios and fresh basil, and serve immediately with the warm whole-wheat pita wedges.	Swap the chopped pistachios for toasted slivered almonds or walnuts.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; reheat the tomato mixture before assembling.	471 kcal	33.1 g	11.0 g	51.1 g	17.2 g	3.1 g	10.9 g	0.0 g*	305 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\blistered_tomato_and_artichoke_cottage_cheese_bowls.png
Caribbean Shrimp, Mango, and Quinoa Bowls	This incredibly fast bowl requires only a quick sear for the shrimp. Sweet mango balances zesty lime, mild quinoa, and hearty black beans for a refreshing, flavor-packed meal.	10 min	3–4 min	8 oz (225 g) Raw peeled shrimp (tail-off), untreated	4.5 oz (130 g) Ready-to-eat cooked plain quinoa	4.6 oz (130 g) No-salt-added canned black beans, rinsed and drained	3.5 oz (100 g) Fresh mango, diced	3.5 oz (100 g) Red bell pepper, diced	1 oz (28 g) Scallions, thinly sliced	0.3 oz (8 g) Fresh cilantro, roughly chopped	2 tbsp (30 ml) Lime juice	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1/4 tsp (1 g) Crushed red pepper flakes				Heat half the olive oil in a nonstick skillet over medium-high heat until shimmering.	Add the shrimp and red pepper flakes, cooking for 3 to 4 minutes, flipping once, until the shrimp are pink and opaque throughout.	Remove the skillet from the heat and set aside.	Whisk the lime juice and the remaining olive oil together in a large mixing bowl.	Add the quinoa, black beans, mango, bell pepper, scallions, and cilantro to the bowl, tossing gently to coat the ingredients evenly in the dressing.	Divide the quinoa and mango salad between two shallow bowls, top with the seared shrimp, and serve immediately.		Swap the shrimp for diced boneless, skinless chicken breast.	Keeps up to 2 days refrigerated in an airtight container.	348 kcal	30.8 g	8.8 g	37.8 g	9.5 g	1.4 g	10.3 g	0.0 g*	235 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\caribbean_shrimp,_mango,_and_quinoa_bowls.png	Cozy Chicken, Mushroom, and Wild Rice Soup	Relying on a single pot and ready-to-use ingredients, this quick-simmering soup is simple to prepare. It pairs lean chicken breast, earthy mushrooms, and wild rice for a comforting, balanced bowl.	10 min	13–18 min	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	6 oz (170 g) Thin-sliced boneless, skinless chicken breasts, chopped into bite-sized pieces	8 oz (225 g) Cremini mushrooms, sliced	1 1/2 cups (165 g) Carrots, pre-shredded	1 tsp (3 g) Garlic powder	1 tsp (1 g) Fresh thyme, chopped	3 cups (720 ml) Low-sodium chicken broth	1 1/2 cups (210 g) Pre-cooked brown and wild rice blend, from a ready-to-eat pouch	3 cups (90 g) Fresh baby spinach	1 tbsp (15 ml) Apple cider vinegar				Heat oil in a pot over medium-high heat until shimmering. Add chicken and cook for 3 to 4 minutes, checking at 3 minutes, until lightly browned.	Stir in mushrooms and carrots. Cook for 4 to 5 minutes, checking at 4 minutes, until the mushrooms soften and release their liquid.	Stir in garlic powder and thyme. Cook for 1 to 2 minutes, checking at 1 minute, until fragrant.	Pour in broth and wild rice. Bring to a rolling boil, then reduce heat to low and simmer for 5 to 7 minutes, checking at 5 minutes, until heated through.	Remove the pot from the heat. Stir in spinach and vinegar until the leaves are wilted, then portion into bowls.			Swap the chicken for a can of rinsed cannellini beans.	Keeps 3 days refrigerated; reheat gently on the stovetop.	427 kcal	34.3 g	5.9 g	46.8 g	12.9 g	2.4 g	6.8 g	0.0 g*	251 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\cozy_chicken,_mushroom,_and_wild_rice_soup.png
Creamy Edamame and Basil Soup with Whole-Grain Toast	Velvety and vibrant, this bright green soup transforms convenient freezer staples into a deeply savory, herb-forward bowl.	10 min	6–9 min	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	2 cloves (6 g) Garlic, minced	10.5 oz (300 g) Frozen shelled edamame	2 cups (480 ml) Low-sodium vegetable broth	2 cups (60 g) Fresh baby spinach	1/2 cup (15 g) Fresh basil leaves	1 tbsp (15 ml) Fresh lemon juice	1/8 tsp (0.5 g) Salt	1/4 tsp (0.5 g) Black pepper	1 tbsp (15 g) Unsalted pumpkin seeds (pepitas)	2 slices (70 g) Hearty whole-grain bread, toasted			Heat the extra-virgin olive oil in a medium pot over medium heat until shimmering. Add the garlic and cook for 1 to 2 minutes until fragrant and softened. Check at 1 minute.	Add the frozen shelled edamame and low-sodium vegetable broth. Bring to a rolling boil over medium-high heat, then reduce the heat to low. Simmer for 5 to 7 minutes until the edamame is thoroughly heated and tender. Check at 5 minutes.	Remove the pot from the heat. Stir in the fresh baby spinach, fresh basil leaves, fresh lemon juice, salt, and black pepper until the spinach wilts from the residual heat.	Transfer the mixture carefully to a blender, or use an immersion blender directly in the pot. Blend until the soup is velvety and completely smooth.	Divide the soup between two bowls. Garnish with the unsalted pumpkin seeds and serve immediately with the whole-grain bread on the side.			Swap the pumpkin seeds for toasted slivered almonds.	Keeps 3 days refrigerated in an airtight container; reheat gently.	392 kcal	25.2 g	10.7 g	33.0 g	19.7 g	2.0 g	6.9 g	0.0 g*	429 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\creamy_edamame_and_basil_soup_with_whole-grain_toast.png	Curried Chicken, Apple, and Walnut Salad Pockets	This satisfying lunch is perfect for busy afternoons, swapping heavy mayonnaise for a spiced Greek yogurt dressing. Crisp apples and walnuts add a pleasant crunch, while whole-wheat pitas provide sustained energy.	15 min	none (no-cook)	1/3 cup (75 g) Plain nonfat Greek yogurt	1 tbsp (15 ml) Lemon juice	1 tsp (2 g) Mild curry powder	1/4 tsp (0.5 g) Black pepper	6 oz (170 g) Skinless rotisserie chicken breast, shredded or chopped	1 medium (150 g) Fuji or Honeycrisp apple, cored and chopped	2 stalks (80 g) Celery, chopped	3 tbsp (21 g) Chopped walnuts	2 large (120 g) Whole-wheat pita pockets, halved	2 cups (60 g) Baby spinach				Mix the Greek yogurt, lemon juice, curry powder, and black pepper in a medium bowl.	Fold the shredded chicken, chopped apple, celery, and walnuts into the yogurt mixture until thoroughly coated.	Open the halved pita pockets gently to avoid tearing the seams.	Stuff each pita half with the baby spinach leaves.	Spoon the chicken salad into the pitas over the spinach and serve immediately.			Swap the chopped walnuts for sliced almonds or toasted pecans.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; assemble pitas with spinach just before serving.	449 kcal	39.1 g	7.6 g	51.2 g	11.6 g	1.7 g	14.0 g	0.0 g*	396 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\curried_chicken,_apple,_and_walnut_salad_pockets.png
Deconstructed Beef and Pinto Bean Taco Bowls	Turning a traditional taco into a bowl makes it easy to add extra fiber with crisp greens and brown rice. These base ingredients perfectly support the smoky, savory flavors of the lean beef.	10 min	6–9 min	1 tsp (5 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	10 oz (280 g) 96% lean ground beef	1 tbsp (7 g) Salt-free taco seasoning	1/4 cup (60 ml) Low-sodium beef broth	1 cup (140 g) Ready-to-eat cooked brown rice (from a pouch)	4 cups (150 g) Romaine lettuce, chopped	7 oz (200 g) No-salt-added canned pinto beans, rinsed and drained	1/2 cup (120 g) Fresh pico de gallo	2.5 oz (75 g) Avocado, diced	1/4 cup (10 g) Fresh cilantro, chopped				Heat extra-virgin olive oil in a large nonstick skillet over medium-high heat until shimmering.	Add ground beef and salt-free taco seasoning. Cook for 5 to 7 minutes, checking at 5 minutes, while breaking the meat apart with a wooden spoon.	Pour in beef broth, scraping up any browned bits from the bottom of the pan. Simmer for 1 to 2 minutes, checking at 1 minute, then remove from heat.	Warm brown rice in the microwave according to package directions.	Divide chopped romaine lettuce between wide, shallow bowls.	Top the lettuce with the warmed brown rice, rinsed pinto beans, and seasoned beef.	Garnish each bowl with fresh pico de gallo, diced avocado, and chopped cilantro before serving.	Swap the ground beef for extra-lean ground turkey breast.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; store the avocado and greens separately.	514 kcal	41.9 g	13.5 g	48.8 g	17.4 g	4.6 g	3.4 g	0.0 g*	442 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\deconstructed_beef_and_pinto_bean_taco_bowls.png	Deconstructed Spicy Shrimp Sushi Bowls	When you want a satisfying workday lunch without a midday crash, this bowl delivers the exact flavors of a spicy shrimp roll. Pre-cooked shrimp and a quick Greek yogurt dressing keep it filling and entirely effortless.	10 min	none (no-cook)	8 oz (227 g) Frozen cooked shrimp, peeled and tail-off (untreated)	8.8 oz (250 g) Ready-to-eat cooked brown rice pouch	1/4 cup (60 g) Plain nonfat Greek yogurt	2 tsp (10 ml) Sriracha sauce	2 tsp (10 ml) Reduced-sodium soy sauce	1 tbsp (15 ml) Unseasoned rice vinegar	1/2 (150 g) English cucumber, chopped	1/2 cup (50 g) Bagged matchstick carrots	1 small (100 g) Avocado, diced	1 tsp (3 g) Toasted sesame seeds				Place the frozen shrimp in a colander and run under cold water for 5 minutes to thaw, then drain well and pat dry.	Heat the ready-to-eat brown rice pouch in the microwave according to the package directions until softened and warm.	Whisk the yogurt, sriracha, soy sauce, and rice vinegar in a small bowl until completely smooth.	Divide the warmed brown rice evenly between serving bowls.	Top the rice with the thawed shrimp, chopped cucumber, diced avocado, and matchstick carrots.	Drizzle the spicy yogurt dressing evenly over the assembled bowls.	Sprinkle with toasted sesame seeds and serve immediately.	Swap the shrimp for flaked no-salt-added canned pink salmon.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; add the avocado just before serving.	403 kcal	36.3 g	6.8 g	44.4 g	9.9 g	1.6 g	4.9 g	0.8 g*	451 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\deconstructed_spicy_shrimp_sushi_bowls.png
Garlicky Shrimp, Spinach, and White Bean Quesadillas	This satisfying lunch comes together quickly when you need a filling meal to power through the afternoon. The creamy bean mash holds everything together while delivering a substantial fiber boost without heavy melted cheese.	10 min	4–6 min	6 oz (170 g) Frozen cooked peeled shrimp, untreated, thawed, tails removed, and chopped	1 cup (260 g) No-salt-added canned cannellini beans, rinsed and drained	1 tbsp (15 ml) Fresh lemon juice	1 tsp (3 g) Garlic powder	1/2 tsp (1 g) Dried oregano	2 tortillas (90 g) Whole-wheat tortillas (8-inch)	2 cups (60 g) Fresh baby spinach	3 tbsp (20 g) Feta cheese, crumbled	1 tsp (5 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil					Place the frozen shrimp in a bowl of cold water to thaw for 5 minutes. Drain the water, pull off any tails, and chop the shrimp.	Mash the cannellini beans, lemon juice, garlic powder, and dried oregano in a medium bowl until mostly smooth.	Lay the tortillas flat on a clean surface. Spread the bean mash evenly over one half of each tortilla to create a thick base.	Press the chopped shrimp, fresh spinach, and crumbled feta cheese into the bean mash. Fold the bare half over to close the quesadillas.	Heat a large skillet over medium heat and brush the surface with the extra-virgin olive oil.	Add the quesadillas to the skillet. Cook for 2 to 3 minutes until the bottoms are golden brown and crisp.	Flip the quesadillas and cook the other side for 2 to 3 minutes until crisp and the spinach wilts. Cut into wedges and serve.	Trade the shrimp for cooked, shredded skinless chicken breast.	Best enjoyed right away; does not keep.	467 kcal	40.0 g	13.4 g	56.5 g	10.0 g	4.1 g	1.8 g	0.0 g*	528 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\garlicky_shrimp,_spinach,_and_white_bean_quesadillas.png	Greek Chicken and Quinoa Stuffed Peppers	This satisfying lunch is perfect for a busy workday. Using the microwave to steam the bell peppers turns a weekend favorite into a fast, desk-friendly meal that provides steady afternoon energy.	10 min	4–6 min	2 (320 g) Large bell peppers (red or yellow), halved lengthwise and seeded	7 oz (200 g) Shredded skinless rotisserie chicken breast	8.8 oz (250 g) Ready-to-eat cooked quinoa	3.5 oz (100 g) Cherry tomatoes, quartered	2 cups (60 g) Baby spinach, roughly chopped	2 tbsp (30 g) Kalamata olives, pitted, rinsed, drained, and chopped	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	2 tbsp (30 ml) Fresh lemon juice	1/2 tsp (1 g) Dried oregano	2 tbsp (30 g) Crumbled feta cheese				Place the bell pepper halves cut-side down in a microwave-safe dish with water. Cover with a microwave-safe lid and microwave on high for 4 to 6 minutes.	Remove the dish from the microwave and drain any excess water. Flip the peppers cut-side up to cool.	Whisk the extra-virgin olive oil, fresh lemon juice, and dried oregano together in a mixing bowl.	Add the shredded chicken, cooked quinoa, cherry tomatoes, baby spinach, and kalamata olives to the bowl. Toss the ingredients together until the spinach softens and the mixture is coated.	Spoon the chicken and quinoa filling into the steamed bell pepper halves.	Top each stuffed pepper with the crumbled feta cheese.	Serve the stuffed peppers immediately or let them cool entirely to pack in airtight containers.	Swap the chicken for small, untreated cooked shrimp.	Keeps 2-3 days refrigerated; enjoy cold or gently heated.	497 kcal	41.6 g	6.9 g	42.8 g	18.4 g	4.6 g	2.8 g	0.0 g*	400 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\greek_chicken_and_quinoa_stuffed_peppers.png
Ground Chicken and Kidney Bean Minestrone	A satisfying lunch or quick weeknight dinner, this one-pot soup brings Italian-inspired comfort without heavy meats. Lean chicken and fiber-rich kidney beans help stabilize afternoon energy levels.	5 min	16–19 min	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1/2 medium (80 g) Yellow onion, chopped	2 cloves (6 g) Garlic cloves, minced	6 oz (170 g) Lean ground chicken	1 tsp (2 g) Italian seasoning blend	1 1/2 cups (360 ml) Low-sodium chicken broth	7 oz (200 g) No-salt-added canned diced tomatoes, with juices	1/2 cup (130 g) No-salt-added canned dark red kidney beans, rinsed and drained	1.5 oz (42 g) Whole wheat short pasta (like rotini)	1/2 cup (75 g) Frozen chopped spinach				Heat olive oil in a medium pot over medium-high heat.	Add chopped onion, minced garlic, and ground chicken, and cook for 5 to 6 minutes while breaking the meat apart with a wooden spoon until browned.	Stir in Italian seasoning, chicken broth, diced tomatoes, kidney beans, and pasta.	Bring the soup to a boil, then reduce the heat to low, cover, and simmer for 9 to 11 minutes, checking the pasta for tenderness at 9 minutes.	Stir in frozen spinach and simmer for 2 more minutes until wilted and heated through.			Swap the spinach for chopped kale or the chicken for turkey.	Keeps 3 days refrigerated; reheat gently on the stovetop.	394 kcal	27.5 g	9.1 g	37.3 g	16.8 g	3.6 g	7.1 g	0.0 g*	155 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\ground_chicken_and_kidney_bean_minestrone.png	Harvest Salmon and Brown Rice Salad Bowls	Swapping heavy mayonnaise for a bright apple cider vinaigrette turns the classic Waldorf salad into a fresh grain bowl. This no-cook recipe relies on pantry staples for a simple, fiber-rich lunch.	15 min	none (no-cook)	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1 tbsp (15 ml) Apple cider vinegar	1 tsp (5 g) Dijon mustard	1/4 tsp (1.5 g) Salt	1/4 tsp (1 g) Black pepper	1 large (220 g) Large crisp red apple, cored and chopped	2 medium stalks (80 g) Celery, sliced	1 cup (150 g) Ready-to-eat cooked brown rice	8 oz (226 g) No-salt-added canned pink salmon, drained	4 cups (120 g) Mixed baby greens	3 tbsp (21 g) Walnuts, chopped			Whisk the extra-virgin olive oil, apple cider vinegar, Dijon mustard, salt, and black pepper in a large mixing bowl until smooth.	Add the chopped apple, celery, and brown rice to the vinaigrette and toss to coat the ingredients.	Flake the drained salmon with a fork, leaving some larger chunks intact.	Divide the mixed baby greens between two serving bowls.	Spoon the dressed rice, apple, and celery mixture over the greens.	Top each bowl with the flaked salmon and sprinkle with the chopped walnuts.		Swap the pink salmon for drained no-salt-added canned tuna.	Best enjoyed right away to keep the greens crisp.	469 kcal	27.1 g	5.9 g	40.8 g	21.8 g	3.6 g	14.1 g	0.0 g*	453 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\harvest_salmon_and_brown_rice_salad_bowls.png
Lemon-Garlic Chicken and White Bean Soup	This comforting soup relies on fiber-rich white beans and lean ground chicken to provide steady energy and keep you full. Lemon juice and aromatic herbs build deep flavor without relying on heavy cream or extra salt.	5 min	14–18 min	2 tsp (10 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	8 oz (225 g) 93% lean ground chicken	1 cup (115 g) Frozen mirepoix blend	3 cloves (9 g) Fresh garlic, minced	1 tsp (1 g) Dried Italian seasoning	2 cups (480 ml) Low-sodium chicken broth	9 oz (255 g) No-salt-added canned Great Northern beans, rinsed and drained	2 cups (60 g) Fresh baby spinach	1 tbsp (15 ml) Fresh lemon juice					Heat the extra-virgin olive oil in a medium pot or Dutch oven over medium-high heat until shimmering.	Add the ground chicken and break it apart with a wooden spoon. Cook for 3 to 4 minutes until no longer pink.	Stir in the frozen mirepoix blend and minced garlic. Sauté for 3 to 4 minutes until the vegetables soften and smell fragrant.	Mix in the dried Italian seasoning, low-sodium chicken broth, and rinsed Great Northern beans. Bring the liquid to a rolling boil over medium-high heat.	Reduce the heat to medium-low to maintain a gentle simmer. Cover the pot partially and cook for 8 to 10 minutes to allow the flavors to combine.	Remove the pot from the heat. Stir in the fresh baby spinach and fresh lemon juice, folding until the spinach wilts.	Ladle the soup into bowls and serve immediately.	Swap the ground chicken for lean ground turkey or tofu.	Keeps 3 days refrigerated; reheat gently on the stovetop.	447 kcal	37.0 g	9.5 g	40.9 g	16.5 g	4.0 g	2.5 g	0.0 g*	417 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\lemon-garlic_chicken_and_white_bean_soup.png	Mediterranean Artichoke, Chicken, and Farro Bowls	This bright, lemony bowl delivers steady afternoon energy by pairing lean protein with high-fiber farro and vegetables. Relying on simple pantry staples helps you assemble a satisfying lunch without turning on the stove.	10 min	none (no-cook)	8.8 oz (250 g) Ready-to-eat cooked farro pouch	10 oz (280 g) No-salt-added canned chicken breast, drained	8.5 oz (240 g) No-salt-added canned quartered artichoke hearts (in water), rinsed and drained	5 oz (150 g) Cherry tomatoes	1/4 cup (15 g) Fresh flat-leaf parsley	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	2 tbsp (30 ml) Fresh lemon juice	1/2 tsp (1.5 g) Garlic powder	1/4 tsp (1.5 g) Kosher salt	1/4 tsp (0.5 g) Black pepper				Warm the farro according to the package instructions.	Halve the cherry tomatoes and chop the parsley while the farro warms.	Whisk the olive oil, lemon juice, garlic powder, salt, and black pepper together in a large mixing bowl.	Add the warm farro, drained chicken, drained artichoke hearts, tomatoes, and parsley to the bowl.	Toss to combine, breaking the chicken apart into bite-sized chunks.	Divide the mixture between plates to serve immediately, or pack into containers for a cold lunch.		Trade the canned chicken for drained light tuna in water.	Keeps 3 days refrigerated in an airtight container; serve cold.	515 kcal	47.2 g	13.2 g	57.0 g	11.5 g	2.1 g	3.6 g	0.0 g*	440 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\mediterranean_artichoke,_chicken,_and_farro_bowls.png
Mediterranean Tuna and White Bean Pita Pockets	Mashing white beans into tuna provides lean protein and steady carbohydrates to keep you full well into the afternoon. Skipping traditional mayonnaise keeps saturated fat low while letting the bright flavors of lemon and fresh vegetables shine.	15 min	none (no-cook)	7 oz (200 g) No-salt-added canned chunk light tuna in water, rinsed and drained	5 oz (150 g) No-salt-added canned cannellini beans, rinsed and drained	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1 1/2 tbsp (22 ml) Lemon juice	1/2 tsp (1 g) Black pepper	1/4 cup (10 g) Fresh parsley, finely chopped	1/4 cup (30 g) Red onion, finely chopped	3.5 oz (100 g) Cucumber, diced	3.5 oz (100 g) Cherry tomatoes, quartered	2 medium (128 g) Whole-wheat pitas				Place the drained cannellini beans in a medium mixing bowl and mash with a fork until mostly smooth, leaving a few chunks for texture.	Add the drained tuna to the bowl with the mashed beans. Pour in the olive oil and lemon juice, sprinkle with black pepper, and mix thoroughly.	Fold the chopped parsley, red onion, cucumber, and cherry tomatoes into the tuna mixture until evenly combined.	Cut the whole-wheat pitas in half to create pockets and pry each one open.	Spoon the filling into the pita pockets and serve immediately.			Swap the canned tuna for flaked, untreated canned pink salmon.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; assemble in fresh pitas just before serving.	483 kcal	40.2 g	10.1 g	61.2 g	9.9 g	1.5 g	5.4 g	0.0 g*	331 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\mediterranean_tuna_and_white_bean_pita_pockets.png	Open-Faced Waldorf Chicken Salad Sandwiches	Swapping mayonnaise for Greek yogurt transforms this deli classic into a practical weekday lunch. Fresh grapes add natural sweetness and crunch, creating a bright salad that pairs perfectly with whole-grain bread.	10 min	none (no-cook)	1/2 cup (115 g) Plain nonfat Greek yogurt	2 tsp (10 g) Dijon mustard	1 tbsp (15 ml) Fresh lemon juice	1/2 tsp (1 g) Black pepper	7 oz (200 g) No-salt-added canned chicken breast, rinsed and drained	1/2 cup (80 g) Celery, diced	1 cup (150 g) Red grapes, halved	1 oz (28 g) Walnuts, chopped	4 slices (140 g) Dense whole-grain bread	2 cups (40 g) Baby arugula				Whisk the yogurt, Dijon mustard, lemon juice, and black pepper together in a medium mixing bowl.	Flake the drained chicken into the bowl using a fork.	Fold the diced celery, halved grapes, and chopped walnuts into the yogurt mixture until evenly coated.	Lay the whole-grain bread slices flat on serving plates.	Divide the arugula evenly across the bread slices.	Spoon the chicken salad over the arugula and serve immediately.		Swap the chopped walnuts for unsalted chopped pecans or almonds.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; add the arugula just before serving.	490 kcal	43.4 g	7.1 g	50.5 g	14.3 g	2.0 g	18.1 g	0.0 g*	484 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\open-faced_waldorf_chicken_salad_sandwiches.png
Peanut-Lime Chicken and Whole-Wheat Noodle Salad	This incredibly simple lunch relies on a no-cook dressing and quick boiling to keep prep time short. It combines whole-wheat spaghetti, lean rotisserie chicken breast, and crisp pre-shredded cabbage slaw in a tangy peanut sauce.	10 min	10–12 min	3.5 oz (100 g) 100% whole-wheat spaghetti	6 oz (170 g) Skinless rotisserie chicken breast, shredded or chopped	6 oz (170 g) Pre-shredded cabbage slaw mix	4 oz (115 g) English cucumber, thinly sliced into half-moons	1.5 tbsp (24 g) Natural peanut butter, no added sugar	2 tbsp (30 ml) Fresh lime juice	2 tsp (10 ml) Low-sodium soy sauce	1 clove (3 g) Fresh garlic, minced	1/2 tsp (1 g) Red pepper flakes					Bring a medium pot of water to a rolling boil over high heat.	Add the spaghetti and cook for 10 to 12 minutes, or until tender.	Drain the pasta and rinse briefly under cold water to cool it down quickly. Transfer to a large mixing bowl.	Whisk the peanut butter, lime juice, soy sauce, garlic, red pepper flakes, and 1 tablespoon of warm water in a small bowl until smooth.	Add the shredded chicken, cabbage slaw mix, and sliced cucumber to the bowl with the cooled pasta.	Pour the peanut dressing over the salad and toss well to coat all the ingredients evenly.	Divide the noodle salad between two plates and serve immediately, or pack for lunch.	Swap the chicken for shelled edamame to make it vegetarian.	Keeps 2-3 days refrigerated; best enjoyed cold or at room temperature.	428 kcal	38.1 g	7.9 g	48.7 g	10.9 g	2.4 g	6.7 g	0.0 g*	265 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\peanut-lime_chicken_and_whole-wheat_noodle_salad.png	Smashed Tofu and Chickpea Dill Salad Pockets	Creamy, tangy, and packed with fresh herbs, this zero-cook deli-style salad uses crumbled tofu and mashed chickpeas to deliver a satisfying, high-fiber lunch.	15 min	none (no-cook)	8.8 oz (250 g) Extra-firm tofu, drained and patted dry	4.5 oz (130 g) No-salt-added canned chickpeas, rinsed and drained	5.3 oz (150 g) Nonfat plain Greek yogurt	1.4 oz (40 g) Celery, finely diced	1 oz (30 g) Red onion, finely diced	1 tbsp (15 ml) Fresh lemon juice	2 tsp (10 g) Dijon mustard	2 tbsp (6 g) Fresh dill, finely chopped	2 pitas (128 g) Whole-wheat pita breads (6-inch)	2 oz (60 g) Mixed salad greens				Place the tofu and chickpeas in a medium mixing bowl.	Mash the mixture with a sturdy fork or potato masher until crumbled but still slightly chunky.	Fold the yogurt, celery, red onion, lemon juice, Dijon mustard, and dill into the mashed mixture until well combined.	Cut the pita breads in half to create pockets.	Line the inside of each pita pocket with the mixed salad greens.	Spoon the tofu and chickpea salad into the pockets and serve.		Swap the fresh dill for chopped cilantro or flat-leaf parsley.	Keeps 3 days refrigerated; store the salad and pita separately.	428 kcal	32.7 g	11.4 g	58.4 g	9.9 g	1.5 g	9.8 g	0.0 g*	390 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\smashed_tofu_and_chickpea_dill_salad_pockets.png
Smoky Salmon and Sweet Corn Chowder	This hearty New England-inspired chowder relies on tender potatoes and a partial mash to build creaminess naturally. Salmon and sweet corn keep the bowl satisfying without the need for heavy cream.	10 min	18–22 min	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	3.5 oz (100 g) Yellow onion, finely chopped	4.2 oz (120 g) Celery, chopped	2 tsp (4 g) Smoked paprika	5.3 oz (150 g) Baby red potatoes, diced small	7 oz (200 g) Frozen sweet corn	1 cup (240 ml) Low-sodium vegetable broth	6 oz (170 g) No-salt-added canned pink salmon, drained and flaked	1 cup (240 ml) Low-fat (1%) milk	2 tbsp (6 g) Fresh chives, chopped				Heat the oil in a medium pot over medium heat until shimmering, then add the onion and celery and cook for 4 to 5 minutes until softened.	Stir in the smoked paprika and cook for 30 seconds until fragrant.	Add the potatoes, sweet corn, and vegetable broth, and bring the mixture to a gentle simmer over medium-high heat.	Reduce the heat to medium-low, cover the pot, and simmer for 10 to 12 minutes, checking the potatoes with a fork to ensure they are tender.	Mash a portion of the potatoes and corn directly in the pot using a potato masher or the back of a large spoon to naturally thicken the chowder.	Stir in the flaked salmon and the milk, and warm the chowder over medium-low heat for 3 to 4 minutes, ensuring the liquid does not boil.	Remove the pot from the heat, divide the chowder between bowls, and top with the fresh chives.	Swap the pink salmon for drained no-salt-added canned white tuna.	Keeps 2-3 days refrigerated; reheat gently on the stovetop.	416 kcal	26.7 g	6.1 g	47.1 g	15.1 g	3.3 g	14.4 g	0.0 g*	253 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\smoky_salmon_and_sweet_corn_chowder.png	Smoky Shrimp, Tomato, and Whole Grain Stew	Smoked paprika and a splash of sherry vinegar deliver the savory depth of a classic Spanish seafood stew without the excess saturated fat. Adding a ready-to-eat grain pouch directly into the simmering broth builds a hearty, thick texture instantly.	5 min	11–16 min	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1 1/2 cups (150 g) Frozen bell pepper and onion blend	2 tsp (4 g) Smoked paprika	1 tsp (3 g) Garlic powder	1 cup (240 ml) Low-sodium vegetable broth	1 can (14.5 oz / 411 g) No-salt-added diced tomatoes	7 oz (200 g) Ready-to-eat brown rice and quinoa pouch	9 oz (250 g) Frozen pre-cooked shrimp (untreated / no salt added), thawed	1 tbsp (15 ml) Sherry vinegar	1/4 cup (15 g) Fresh parsley, chopped				Heat the olive oil in a medium pot over medium-high heat. Add the frozen pepper and onion blend, and sauté until softened, 3 to 4 minutes.	Stir in the smoked paprika and garlic powder. Cook until fragrant, about 30 seconds.	Pour in the vegetable broth and diced tomatoes with their juices. Bring to a rolling boil over medium-high heat, reduce the heat to low, and simmer until the tomatoes break down slightly, 5 to 6 minutes.	Stir the brown rice and quinoa into the simmering broth. Cook until the grains absorb some of the liquid and warm through, 2 to 3 minutes.	Fold in the thawed shrimp and sherry vinegar. Simmer until the shrimp are hot and opaque, 1 to 2 minutes.	Remove the pot from the heat immediately to prevent the shrimp from overcooking. Stir in the parsley and portion the stew into warm bowls.		Trade the shrimp for diced, roasted chicken breast pieces.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; reheat gently on the stovetop.	389 kcal	36.1 g	7.7 g	41.2 g	9.9 g	1.5 g	9.1 g	0.0 g*	244 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\smoky_shrimp,_tomato,_and_whole_grain_stew.png
Smoky Tempeh, White Bean, and Kale Soup	Crumbled tempeh acts as a hearty, savory stand-in for traditional ground sausage in this fast, one-pot soup. It delivers plant-based protein without the saturated fat found in cured meats.	10 min	12–15 min	2 tsp (10 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	6 oz (170 g) Tempeh, crumbled	1 tsp (2 g) Smoked paprika	1 tsp (3 g) Garlic powder	2 cups (480 ml) Low-sodium vegetable broth	8 oz (225 g) No-salt-added canned diced tomatoes, undrained	7 oz (200 g) No-salt-added canned cannellini beans, rinsed and drained	2 cups (42 g) Fresh kale, stemmed and chopped	1 tbsp (15 ml) Red wine vinegar	1/4 tsp (1.5 g) Salt				Warm extra-virgin olive oil in a medium pot over medium-high heat.	Add crumbled tempeh and sauté for 4 to 5 minutes until lightly browned.	Stir in smoked paprika and garlic powder, cooking for 30 seconds until fragrant.	Pour in vegetable broth, diced tomatoes, and cannellini beans, and bring the mixture to a boil.	Reduce heat to low, stir in chopped kale, and cover the pot.	Simmer for 5 to 7 minutes, checking at 5 minutes to ensure the kale is tender.	Remove from heat, stir in red wine vinegar and salt, and ladle the soup into bowls.	Swap the chopped fresh kale for fresh baby spinach.	Keeps 3 days refrigerated; reheat gently on the stovetop.	395 kcal	29.4 g	9.8 g	40.5 g	15.5 g	3.0 g	4.8 g	0.0 g*	468 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\smoky_tempeh,_white_bean,_and_kale_soup.png	Southwestern Chicken and Black Bean Mason Jar Salad	This desk-friendly salad builds a robust meal for busy weekdays without relying on heavy bottled dressings. The layered approach keeps the greens crisp until you are ready to shake and eat.	15 min	none (no-cook)	2 tbsp (30 ml) Fresh lime juice	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1/4 cup (4 g) Fresh cilantro, finely chopped	1 tsp (2 g) Ground cumin	1/4 tsp (1.5 g) Kosher salt	1 cup (150 g) Cherry tomatoes, halved	1/2 cup (130 g) Canned black beans, no-salt-added, rinsed and drained	1/2 cup (70 g) Frozen whole kernel corn, thawed	1/2 cup (90 g) Plain quinoa, cooked and cooled	6 oz (170 g) Cooked chicken breast, chopped	3 cups (140 g) Romaine lettuce, chopped			Whisk the lime juice, olive oil, cilantro, cumin, and salt in a small bowl to make the dressing.	Divide the dressing into the bottom of large mason jars or tall storage containers.	Layer the halved cherry tomatoes directly into the dressing.	Add the rinsed black beans, thawed corn, and cooked quinoa in even layers on top of the tomatoes.	Place the chopped cooked chicken over the grains and beans.	Pack the chopped romaine lettuce into the top of the jars and secure with lids.	Shake the jars before serving to distribute the dressing over the greens.	Swap the cooked chicken for drained canned low-sodium tuna.	Keeps 2 to 3 days refrigerated in sealed jars.	379 kcal	35.1 g	9.1 g	34.6 g	12.0 g	2.1 g	4.5 g	0.0 g*	460 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\southwestern_chicken_and_black_bean_mason_jar_salad.png
Southwestern Turkey, Corn, and White Bean Chili	A hearty serving of lean protein and dietary fiber helps keep your energy steady through the afternoon. Using low-sodium canned staples means this earthy, comforting bowl is ready without the traditional all-day simmer.	10 min	13–16 min	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1/2 cup (80 g) Yellow onion, chopped	8 oz (227 g) Lean ground turkey (93% lean)	1 tsp (2 g) Ground cumin	1/2 tsp (1.5 g) Garlic powder	1 cup (170 g) No-salt-added canned cannellini beans, rinsed and drained	1 cup (130 g) Frozen sweet corn	4 oz (113 g) Low-sodium diced green chiles, drained	1 cup (240 ml) Low-sodium chicken broth	1/2 cup (120 ml) Water	1 tbsp (15 ml) Fresh lime juice	2 tbsp (5 g) Fresh cilantro, chopped		Heat oil in a medium pot or Dutch oven over medium-high heat. Add chopped onion and cook until it starts to soften, about 3 minutes.	Add turkey, cumin, and garlic powder to the pot. Cook, breaking meat apart with a spoon, until no longer pink, about 4 to 5 minutes.	Stir in drained beans, corn, drained green chiles, broth, and water. Bring mixture to a rolling boil.	Reduce heat to medium-low to maintain a gentle simmer. Cook uncovered to blend flavors, about 6 to 8 minutes.	Remove pot from heat. Stir in lime juice and chopped cilantro just before serving.			Swap the ground turkey for an equal amount of ground chicken.	Keeps 3 days refrigerated; reheat on the stovetop or microwave.	462 kcal	35.1 g	8.5 g	44.3 g	18.3 g	3.8 g	6.3 g	0.0 g*	150 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\southwestern_turkey,_corn,_and_white_bean_chili.png	Spiced Beef, Herb, and Bulgur Salad Bowls	Fragrant, warm Mediterranean spices mingle with bright lemon and fresh parsley in these hearty grain bowls. Lean ground beef provides satisfying protein while crisp cucumbers and tomatoes bulk up the salad without adding saturated fat.	15 min	10–12 min	3/4 cup (180 ml) Water	1/2 cup (70 g) Quick-cooking bulgur wheat	8 oz (225 g) Lean ground beef (95% lean)	2 cloves (6 g) Fresh garlic, minced	1 tsp (2 g) Ground cumin	1/2 tsp (1 g) Ground allspice	1/4 tsp (1.5 g) Salt	1 cup (150 g) Cherry tomatoes, halved	5 oz (150 g) English cucumber, diced	1 cup (30 g) Fresh flat-leaf parsley, chopped	2 tbsp (30 ml) Fresh lemon juice	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	2 tbsp (14 g) Sliced almonds	Bring the water to a boil in a small saucepan over high heat. Stir in the bulgur, reduce heat to low, cover, and simmer for 10 to 12 minutes. Check at 10 minutes to ensure the liquid is absorbed and grains are tender; remove from heat.	Heat a nonstick skillet over medium-high heat. Add the ground beef, garlic, cumin, allspice, and salt.	Cook for 5 to 7 minutes, breaking the meat apart with a wooden spoon, until browned. Check at 5 minutes to ensure no pink remains; remove from heat.	Whisk the lemon juice and olive oil together in a large mixing bowl.	Add the cooked bulgur, cherry tomatoes, cucumber, and parsley to the dressing; toss gently to coat.	Divide the bulgur salad between two bowls. Top each with the spiced beef and sprinkle with the sliced almonds before serving.		Swap the ground beef for lean ground turkey breast.	Keeps 2 to 3 days refrigerated; store beef and salad separately.	421 kcal	31.9 g	7.2 g	37.4 g	17.4 g	3.9 g	4.3 g	0.0 g*	391 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\spiced_beef,_herb,_and_bulgur_salad_bowls.png
Spiced Tilapia and Orange Quinoa Bowls	This quick bowl relies on a fast stovetop sear and a ready-to-eat grain base for an easy dinner. Warm, spiced tilapia fillets pair perfectly with juicy navel orange segments and peppery arugula for a satisfying meal.	10 min	6–8 min	8 oz (225 g) Tilapia fillets	1 tsp (2 g) Smoked paprika	1/2 tsp (1 g) Ground cumin	1/4 tsp (1 g) Kosher salt	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil, divided	8.8 oz (250 g) Ready-to-eat cooked quinoa, from a microwaveable pouch	3 oz (85 g) Baby arugula	1 large (150 g) Navel orange, peeled and segmented	1/2 medium (70 g) Avocado, sliced	3 medium (45 g) Radishes, thinly sliced	1 tbsp (15 ml) Fresh lime juice			Pat the tilapia dry with a paper towel. Rub both sides evenly with the smoked paprika, ground cumin, and salt.	Heat a portion of the olive oil in a large nonstick skillet over medium-high heat until shimmering. Add the tilapia and cook for 3 to 4 minutes per side, flipping halfway through, until the crust is golden and the fish flakes easily with a fork.	Warm the cooked quinoa in the microwave according to the pouch instructions.	Whisk the lime juice and the remaining olive oil in a small bowl to create a dressing.	Divide the arugula and warmed quinoa between two wide, shallow bowls.	Arrange the seared tilapia, orange segments, sliced avocado, and radishes over the greens and grains.	Drizzle the lime dressing evenly across both bowls just before serving.	Swap the tilapia for peeled shrimp and sear until pink.	Best enjoyed right away; greens will wilt if stored dressed.	438 kcal	31.0 g	9.0 g	42.7 g	17.6 g	2.8 g	9.2 g	0.0 g*	286 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\spiced_tilapia_and_orange_quinoa_bowls.png	Tuscan Chicken and Smashed White Bean Wraps	This satisfying lunch is perfect to assemble ahead of time and eat at your desk. Smashed cannellini beans stand in for mayonnaise to bind this herb-packed chicken salad while keeping you full for hours.	10 min	none (no-cook)	1/2 cup (130 g) No-salt-added canned cannellini beans, rinsed and drained	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1 tbsp (15 ml) Lemon juice	1/2 tsp (2 g) Garlic powder	1/2 tsp (1 g) Dried oregano	5.5 oz (150 g) Skinless rotisserie chicken breast, chopped	1/4 cup (20 g) Sun-dried tomatoes (dry-packed), chopped	1/2 cup (100 g) No-salt-added canned artichoke hearts (water-packed), rinsed, drained, and roughly chopped	2 large (120 g) 100% whole-wheat tortillas	2 cups (40 g) Fresh baby spinach				Place the beans in a medium bowl and mash with a fork until mostly smooth.	Stir the olive oil, lemon juice, garlic powder, and oregano into the mashed beans until combined.	Fold the chicken, sun-dried tomatoes, and artichoke hearts into the bean mixture until coated.	Lay the whole-wheat tortillas flat on a clean work surface and divide the spinach between them.	Spoon the chicken and bean salad over the spinach and spread into an even layer.	Fold the sides of each tortilla inward and roll tightly from the bottom to form a wrap.	Slice the wraps in half diagonally and serve.	Swap the artichoke hearts for chopped roasted red peppers.	Keeps up to 2 days refrigerated; enjoy cold.	525 kcal	39.1 g	14.7 g	57.5 g	16.4 g	4.8 g	6.2 g	0.0 g*	494 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\tuscan_chicken_and_smashed_white_bean_wraps.png
Tuscan Mackerel and White Bean Stuffed Tomatoes	This totally zero-cook assembly is ready in minutes with minimal chopping. Flaky mackerel and creamy white beans make a satisfying filling for fresh tomatoes.	15 min	none (no-cook)	2 large (400 g) Beefsteak tomatoes	8 oz (225 g) No-salt-added canned skinless boneless mackerel in water, drained	3/4 cup (130 g) No-salt-added canned cannellini beans, rinsed and drained	2 tbsp (18 g) Kalamata olives, pitted and finely chopped	1/4 cup (15 g) Fresh flat-leaf parsley, chopped	1 tbsp (15 ml) Lemon juice	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1/2 tsp (1 g) Black pepper	3.5 oz (100 g) Whole-wheat pita bread					Slice the top off each tomato and scoop out the seeds and core with a spoon, leaving a hollow shell. Set aside.	Place the beans in a medium bowl and mash lightly with a fork until mostly broken down but still textured.	Add the drained mackerel, olives, parsley, lemon juice, olive oil, and black pepper to the mashed beans. Fold gently to combine without completely turning the fish to paste.	Spoon the mackerel mixture evenly into the hollowed tomatoes, pressing lightly to fill the cavities.	Cut the whole-wheat pita bread into wedges and serve alongside the stuffed tomatoes.			Swap the cannellini beans for no-salt-added canned chickpeas.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated in an airtight container.	515 kcal	39.5 g	10.1 g	53.9 g	17.1 g	3.6 g	7.2 g	0.0 g*	385 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\tuscan_mackerel_and_white_bean_stuffed_tomatoes.png	Velvety Butternut Squash and White Bean Soup	Skipping the peeling and chopping by using frozen butternut squash makes this hearty soup fast to prepare. Blended white beans create a creamy texture, finished with a dollop of Greek yogurt and crunchy pumpkin seeds.	5 min	15–19 min	2 tsp (10 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	8.8 oz (250 g) Frozen diced butternut squash	1 tsp (3 g) Garlic powder	1 tsp (3 g) Onion powder	1/2 tsp (1 g) Dried sage	2 cups (480 ml) Low-sodium vegetable broth	7 oz (200 g) No-salt-added canned Great Northern beans, rinsed and drained	1/4 tsp (1 g) Salt	1/4 tsp (1 g) Black pepper	4 oz (113 g) Nonfat plain Greek yogurt	1.5 oz (40 g) Unsalted roasted pumpkin seeds (pepitas)			Heat the olive oil in a medium pot over medium heat for 1 to 2 minutes, checking at 1 minute, until shimmering.	Add the frozen butternut squash, garlic powder, onion powder, and dried sage. Sauté for 4 to 5 minutes, checking at 4 minutes, until the squash softens.	Pour in the vegetable broth and stir in the rinsed Great Northern beans, salt, and black pepper. Bring to a boil over medium-high heat, then reduce the heat to medium-low. Simmer for 10 to 12 minutes, checking at 10 minutes, until the squash is tender.	Remove the pot from the heat. Purée the soup directly in the pot using an immersion blender until completely smooth.	Ladle the soup into bowls. Dollop the Greek yogurt into the center of each bowl and sprinkle with the pumpkin seeds before serving.			Swap the dried sage for an equal amount of dried thyme.	Keeps 3-4 days refrigerated; reheat gently on the stovetop.	402 kcal	22.3 g	8.5 g	49.3 g	15.6 g	2.7 g	8.6 g	0.0 g*	539 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Lunch\IMG\velvety_butternut_squash_and_white_bean_soup.png
