Title_1	Introduction_1	Preparation_time_1	Cooking_1	Ingredient_1_1	Ingredient_2_1	Ingredient_3_1	Ingredient_4_1	Ingredient_5_1	Ingredient_6_1	Ingredient_7_1	Ingredient_8_1	Ingredient_9_1	Ingredient_10_1	Ingredient_11_1	Ingredient_12_1	Ingredient_13_1	Instruction_1_1	Instruction_2_1	Instruction_3_1	Instruction_4_1	Instruction_5_1	Instruction_6_1	Instruction_7_1	Variation_1	Storage_1	Calories_1	Protein_1	Fiber_1	Carbs_1	TotalFat_1	SaturatedFat_1	TotalSugars_1	AddedSugars_1	Sodium_1	@Image_1	Title_2	Introduction_2	Preparation_time_2	Cooking_2	Ingredient_1_2	Ingredient_2_2	Ingredient_3_2	Ingredient_4_2	Ingredient_5_2	Ingredient_6_2	Ingredient_7_2	Ingredient_8_2	Ingredient_9_2	Ingredient_10_2	Ingredient_11_2	Ingredient_12_2	Ingredient_13_2	Instruction_1_2	Instruction_2_2	Instruction_3_2	Instruction_4_2	Instruction_5_2	Instruction_6_2	Instruction_7_2	Variation_2	Storage_2	Calories_2	Protein_2	Fiber_2	Carbs_2	TotalFat_2	SaturatedFat_2	TotalSugars_2	AddedSugars_2	Sodium_2	@Image_2
Chili-Lime Edamame and Sweet Corn Salad	Forget waiting for a pot to boil; combining two colorful freezer staples with a bright citrus dressing creates a satisfying, high-fiber side without the stove.	7 min	none (no-cook)	1 cup (155 g) Frozen shelled edamame	1/2 cup (82 g) Frozen sweet corn kernels	1/4 cup (40 g) Red onion, finely chopped	1.5 tsp (7 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1 tbsp (15 ml) Fresh lime juice	1/2 tsp (1 g) Chili powder	2 tbsp (8 g) Fresh cilantro, chopped							Place the edamame and sweet corn in a microwave-safe bowl.	Microwave on high for 2 to 3 minutes, checking halfway, until both vegetables are completely thawed and just warmed through.	Drain any excess water from the bowl to prevent a soggy salad.	Add the red onion, olive oil, lime juice, and chili powder to the warmed vegetables.	Toss everything well to coat the edamame and corn evenly in the dressing.	Stir in the chopped cilantro just before serving or storing.		Swap the chili powder for ground cumin and smoked paprika.	Keeps 2 to 3 days refrigerated in an airtight container.	164 kcal	10.3 g	5.3 g	17.4 g	7.6 g	0.5 g	4.3 g	0.0 g*	22 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Snack\IMG\chili-lime_edamame_and_sweet_corn_salad.png	Citrus and Pistachio Shaved Brussels Sprouts Slaw	This simple no-cook slaw requires minimal prep and uses convenient ingredients. Pre-shaved Brussels sprouts tenderize perfectly when tossed with fresh orange segments and a tangy vinaigrette.	10 min	none (no-cook)	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1 tbsp (15 ml) Apple cider vinegar	1 tsp (5 g) Dijon mustard	1/8 tsp (0.75 g) Salt	1/4 tsp (0.5 g) Black pepper	1 medium (130 g) Fresh orange, peeled	7 oz (200 g) Bagged shaved Brussels sprouts	1 oz (30 g) Shelled pistachios, roughly chopped						Whisk the extra-virgin olive oil, apple cider vinegar, Dijon mustard, salt, and black pepper in a large mixing bowl until smooth.	Cut the peeled orange into bite-sized segments and discard any seeds.	Add the shaved Brussels sprouts and orange segments to the bowl with the dressing.	Toss the salad thoroughly and massage the Brussels sprouts to help them absorb the liquid and soften.	Chop the pistachios.	Sprinkle the chopped pistachios over the slaw before serving.		Swap the orange segments for diced crisp green apple.	Keeps 2-3 days refrigerated; add pistachios just before serving.	225 kcal	7.3 g	7.1 g	21.2 g	14.3 g	1.9 g	9.5 g	0.0 g*	199 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Snack\IMG\citrus_and_pistachio_shaved_brussels_sprouts_slaw.png
Garlicky Spinach and Brown Rice Pilaf	Providing steady complex carbohydrates and fiber, this quick side dish helps keep energy levels stable between meals. It transforms simple brown rice with fresh spinach, bright lemon, and crunchy walnuts into an effortless, vegetable-heavy plate.	5 min	4–6 min	2 tsp (10 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	2 cloves (6 g) Garlic cloves, minced	6 oz (170 g) Fresh baby spinach, roughly chopped	1 cup (150 g) Ready-to-eat cooked brown rice pouch	1 tsp (2 g) Lemon zest	1 tbsp (15 ml) Lemon juice	2 tbsp (14 g) Chopped walnuts	1/4 tsp (0.5 g) Black pepper						Heat the extra-virgin olive oil in a large skillet over medium heat until shimmering.	Add the garlic and sauté for 30 to 60 seconds until fragrant but not browned. Check at 30 seconds.	Add the baby spinach in handfuls, tossing constantly for 1 to 2 minutes until fully wilted. Check at 1 minute.	Stir in the cooked brown rice, breaking up any clumps. Cook for 2 to 3 minutes until heated through. Check at 2 minutes.	Remove the skillet from the heat.	Stir in the lemon zest, lemon juice, chopped walnuts, and black pepper.	Divide the pilaf between plates and serve warm.	Swap the chopped walnuts for toasted pine nuts or almonds.	Keeps 2 to 3 days refrigerated; reheat in the microwave.	209 kcal	5.8 g	3.8 g	25.1 g	10.7 g	1.4 g	1.0 g	0.0 g*	71 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Snack\IMG\garlicky_spinach_and_brown_rice_pilaf.png	Hummus, Crispbread, and Vegetable Snack Plates	A balance of plant protein, healthy fats, and complex carbohydrates provides steady afternoon energy without a blood sugar spike. Plenty of fresh vegetables and whole grains deliver lasting fullness.	10 min	none (no-cook)	1/3 cup (80 g) Store-bought traditional hummus	2 slices (18 g) Whole-grain crispbreads	1 cup (100 g) English cucumber, sliced	2/3 cup (100 g) Cherry tomatoes, halved	2 tbsp (18 g) Raw unsalted almonds	1/2 tsp (1 g) Za'atar seasoning or dried oregano	1 tsp (5 ml) Lemon juice							Divide the hummus evenly between two snack plates or airtight meal-prep containers.	Arrange one crispbread slice, the prepared cucumber, cherry tomatoes, and almonds around the hummus on each plate.	Sprinkle the za'atar or oregano evenly over the hummus and the fresh vegetables.	Drizzle the lemon juice lightly over the vegetables just before serving.				Swap the almonds for raw unsalted walnuts or pumpkin seeds.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated in an airtight container.	195 kcal	6.4 g	5.8 g	19.6 g	11.6 g	1.3 g	2.9 g	0.0 g*	216 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Snack\IMG\hummus,_crispbread,_and_vegetable_snack_plates.png
Lemon-Dill Shrimp and Cucumber Bites	Provides a satisfying hit of lean protein to keep energy steady and easily bridge the gap between meals. Thawing ready-to-eat shrimp under cold water creates an instant, refreshing plate with plenty of crisp crunch.	10 min	none (no-cook)	4 oz (115 g) Frozen cooked shrimp (untreated, peeled, tail-off)	5 oz (150 g) English cucumber, sliced into thick rounds	1.3 oz (38 g) Low-sodium whole-wheat woven crackers	1 tbsp (15 ml) Fresh lemon juice	1 tsp (5 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1 tbsp (3 g) Fresh dill, finely chopped	1/4 tsp (0.5 g) Black pepper							Place the frozen shrimp in a colander and run under cold water for 5 to 7 minutes until completely thawed.	Transfer the thawed shrimp to paper towels and pat them thoroughly dry.	Chop the shrimp roughly into small, bite-sized pieces so they will easily balance on the crackers.	Transfer the chopped shrimp to a small bowl and toss with the lemon juice, olive oil, fresh dill, and black pepper.	Arrange the crackers on a serving plate.	Top each cracker with a cucumber round and a spoonful of the herbed shrimp mixture.		Swap the dill for chopped fresh cilantro and a lime squeeze.	Best enjoyed right away to keep the crackers completely crisp.	166 kcal	16.1 g	1.0 g	19.0 g	3.1 g	0.5 g	1.5 g	0.0 g*	70 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Snack\IMG\lemon-dill_shrimp_and_cucumber_bites.png	Lemony Black-Eyed Pea and Tomato Salad	When you need a fast afternoon snack or a vegetable side for a weeknight dinner, this crisp marinated bean salad works perfectly. The lemon and oregano dressing pairs easily with grilled or roasted mains.	10 min	none (no-cook)	1 cup (160 g) Canned no-salt-added black-eyed peas, rinsed and drained	1/2 cup (100 g) Cherry tomatoes, halved	1/2 cup (100 g) Cucumber, diced	1/4 cup (30 g) Red onion, finely chopped	1/4 cup (10 g) Fresh parsley, chopped	1 tbsp (15 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1 tbsp (15 ml) Fresh lemon juice	1 tsp (2 g) Lemon zest	1 tsp (1 g) Dried oregano	1/8 tsp (0.7 g) Salt	1/4 tsp (0.5 g) Black pepper			Whisk the olive oil, lemon juice, lemon zest, oregano, salt, and black pepper together in a medium bowl.	Add the black-eyed peas, cherry tomatoes, cucumber, red onion, and parsley to the bowl.	Toss the salad until all ingredients are coated in the dressing.					Swap the fresh parsley for chopped fresh dill or mint.	Keeps 2 to 3 days refrigerated in an airtight container.	184 kcal	7.4 g	6.9 g	23.4 g	7.7 g	1.1 g	5.9 g	0.0 g*	146 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Snack\IMG\lemony_black-eyed_pea_and_tomato_salad.png
Mediterranean Lentil Salad Stuffed Mini Peppers	Using sweet pepper halves as edible scoops turns a hearty, fiber-rich lentil salad into a satisfying finger food.	15 min	none (no-cook)	8 peppers (120 g) Mini sweet peppers	8.5 oz (240 g) No-salt-added canned brown lentils, rinsed and drained	2.8 oz (80 g) Fresh cucumber, finely diced	0.7 oz (20 g) Kalamata olives, finely chopped	2 tsp (10 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1 tbsp (15 ml) Red wine vinegar	1/2 tsp (1 g) Dried oregano	1/4 tsp (0.5 g) Black pepper						Halve the mini sweet peppers lengthwise and scoop out the seeds and membranes to create hollow boats.	Whisk the olive oil, red wine vinegar, dried oregano, and black pepper in a medium mixing bowl.	Fold the lentils, cucumber, and olives into the dressing and toss to coat the ingredients evenly.	Spoon the lentil mixture into the hollowed sweet pepper halves and serve.				Swap the dried oregano for freshly chopped mint or dill.	Keeps 2 days refrigerated; store the peppers and filling separately.	216 kcal	11.8 g	11.4 g	30.4 g	6.3 g	1.1 g	5.4 g	0.0 g*	80 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Snack\IMG\mediterranean_lentil_salad_stuffed_mini_peppers.png	Parmesan and Pistachio Olive Oil Popcorn	Bringing Mediterranean ingredients to a movie-night classic turns a simple whole grain into a savory, fiber-rich snack. Popping the corn in olive oil and tossing it with crushed pistachios delivers a satisfying crunch that supports steady blood sugar.	5 min	3–5 min	1/4 cup (30 g) Shelled pistachios, roughly chopped	2 tsp (10 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1/4 cup (50 g) Popcorn kernels	3 tbsp (15 g) Grated parmesan cheese	1/2 tsp (2 g) Garlic powder	1/2 tsp (1 g) Dried thyme	1/4 tsp (1 g) Black pepper							Heat the extra-virgin olive oil in a large pot with a tight-fitting lid over medium-high heat. Drop in the test popcorn kernels.	Add the remaining popcorn kernels when the test kernels pop. Cover the pot and remove from the heat for 30 seconds to equalize the temperature.	Return the pot to medium heat.	Shake the pot continuously as the corn pops for 2 to 4 minutes. Check the progress at 2 minutes, and stop shaking when the popping slows to one pop every 2 to 3 seconds.	Remove the pot from the heat immediately. Add the chopped pistachios, grated parmesan cheese, garlic powder, dried thyme, and black pepper directly into the hot pot.	Toss the mixture well so the residual heat warms the nuts and helps the cheese stick.	Transfer the popcorn to a large bowl and serve warm.	Trade the dried thyme for a pinch of smoked paprika.	Best enjoyed right away; does not keep.	255 kcal	7.9 g	5.6 g	25.2 g	14.7 g	2.9 g	1.4 g	0.0 g*	138 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Snack\IMG\parmesan_and_pistachio_olive_oil_popcorn.png
Roasted Red Pepper and Walnut Dip	An ideal mid-afternoon snack to bridge the gap until dinner, this Mediterranean spread recreates the rich flavors of muhammara without the wait. Walnuts lend a creamy body to the dip while providing supportive omega-3 fatty acids.	5 min	none (no-cook)	3/4 cup (120 g) Jarred roasted red peppers, no-salt-added, rinsed and drained well	1/3 cup (40 g) Shelled raw walnuts	1 clove (3 g) Fresh garlic, peeled	1 tbsp (15 ml) Lemon juice	1 tsp (5 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1/2 tsp (1 g) Ground cumin	1/4 tsp (0.5 g) Red pepper flakes	1/8 tsp (0.5 g) Salt	1 small pita (50 g) Whole-wheat pita bread, cut into wedges	1 medium (200 g) Cucumber, sliced into thick rounds				Place the drained roasted red peppers, walnuts, garlic, lemon juice, extra-virgin olive oil, cumin, red pepper flakes, and salt into a small food processor or blender.	Blend on high speed until smooth, scraping down the sides of the bowl with a spatula as needed.	Transfer the dip to a small serving bowl.	Arrange the cucumber rounds and whole-wheat pita wedges on a plate alongside the dip.	Serve immediately using the cucumber and pita to scoop up the dip.			Swap the cucumber slices for crisp celery or carrot sticks.	Keeps 3-4 days refrigerated in an airtight container.	255 kcal	7.0 g	4.4 g	24.7 g	16.4 g	1.7 g	5.6 g	0.0 g*	209 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Snack\IMG\roasted_red_pepper_and_walnut_dip.png	Rosemary Almond and Pepita Mix with Pear	This fast and simple snack requires just a single skillet. Raw almonds and pumpkin seeds are toasted with savory herbs and served alongside fresh pear for an enjoyable crunch.	5 min	4–6 min	3 tbsp (25 g) Raw whole almonds	3 tbsp (25 g) Raw pumpkin seeds (pepitas)	1 tsp (5 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1 tsp (2 g) Fresh rosemary, finely chopped	1/4 tsp (0.7 g) Garlic powder	1/8 tsp (0.3 g) Kosher salt	1 medium (180 g) Fresh pear, cored and sliced							Combine the almonds, pumpkin seeds, olive oil, rosemary, garlic powder, and salt in a small bowl and stir until evenly coated.	Heat a medium dry skillet over medium heat.	Add the nut mixture to the skillet and toast for 4 to 6 minutes. Stir frequently, checking at 4 minutes, until the seeds begin to pop and smell fragrant.	Remove the skillet from the heat and immediately transfer the hot nut mixture to a plate to prevent burning.	Divide the sliced pear between two plates and serve alongside the warm toasted nuts.			Swap the sliced pear for a crisp Granny Smith apple.	Store leftover cooled nuts up to 3 days at room temperature.	218 kcal	6.8 g	5.3 g	18.2 g	15.1 g	2.0 g	9.5 g	0.0 g*	61 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Snack\IMG\rosemary_almond_and_pepita_mix_with_pear.png
Smoky Butter Bean Dip with Sweet Peppers	Silky and boldly spiced, this creamy dip uses tender butter beans to create a satisfying, high-fiber snack.	5 min	none (no-cook)	5 oz (150 g) Canned no-salt-added butter beans, rinsed and drained	1 tbsp (15 ml) Fresh lemon juice	1 tbsp (15 ml) Water	2 tsp (10 ml) Extra-virgin olive oil	1 tbsp (10 g) Unsalted roasted pumpkin seeds (pepitas)	1 clove (3 g) Garlic, peeled and smashed	1/2 tsp (1 g) Smoked paprika	1/8 tsp (0.5 g) Salt	3 oz (80 g) Red bell pepper, sliced into strips	2 oz (60 g) Carrots, cut into sticks				Place the butter beans, lemon juice, olive oil, garlic, smoked paprika, and salt in a food processor or blender.	Blend on high speed until completely smooth and creamy, pulsing in the water if the mixture is too thick.	Transfer the dip to a serving bowl.	Garnish the surface with the roasted pumpkin seeds.	Serve immediately alongside the red bell pepper and carrots for dipping.			Trade the smoked paprika for ground cumin and fresh cilantro.	Keeps up to 3 days refrigerated in an airtight container.	160 kcal	6.0 g	5.5 g	18.7 g	7.8 g	1.1 g	2.9 g	0.0 g*	127 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Snack\IMG\smoky_butter_bean_dip_with_sweet_peppers.png	Warm Cinnamon-Berry Greek Yogurt Bowls with Toasted Oats	This simple six-ingredient snack is completely ready in under ten minutes. A warm compote of frozen mixed berries and cinnamon perfectly complements chilled nonfat Greek yogurt and freshly toasted oats.	5 min	3–5 min	1 1/2 cups (340 g) Nonfat plain Greek yogurt	1 cup (140 g) Frozen mixed berries	1/4 cup (20 g) Old-fashioned rolled oats	1 1/2 tbsp (10 g) Sliced almonds	1/2 tsp (1 g) Ground cinnamon	1/2 tsp (2 ml) Vanilla extract								Place a small, dry skillet over medium heat. Add the oats and sliced almonds.	Toast the mixture, stirring frequently, for 3 to 5 minutes until golden and fragrant. Check at 3 minutes to prevent burning, then transfer to a small dish to cool.	Place the frozen berries in a microwave-safe bowl. Microwave on high for 1 to 2 minutes until hot and juicy, checking at 1 minute.	Mash the warm berries slightly with a fork to release their natural syrup. Stir in the cinnamon and vanilla extract.	Divide the yogurt between two serving bowls.	Spoon the warm berry compote over the yogurt and top with the toasted oat and almond crunch.		Swap the mixed berries for frozen dark sweet cherries.	Best enjoyed right away; does not keep.	202 kcal	20.4 g	3.2 g	21.4 g	4.0 g	0.5 g	10.1 g	0.0 g*	62 mg	C:\Users\terja\Documents\AI_Projects\recipe-generator-fatty-liver-diabetes\data\generated_recipes\cookbook-recipes\Snack\IMG\warm_cinnamon-berry_greek_yogurt_bowls_with_toasted_oats.png
